<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
        <tumblr version="1.0"><posts><post id="175165024416" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/175165024416" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/175165024416/a-piece-of-parchment-found-in-the-chamber-where" type="photo" date-gmt="2018-06-23 07:28:05 GMT" date="Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:28:05" unix-timestamp="1529738885" format="markdown" reblog-key="76WIR0Gt" slug="a-piece-of-parchment-found-in-the-chamber-where" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles" width="1200" height="1600"><photo-caption>&lt;p&gt;A piece of parchment found in the chamber where Tak, rakish bard adventurer, betrayed Levani and dealt her what should have been a killing blow in order to use her blood to release an oversized gem from a magical prison.&lt;/p&gt;</photo-caption><photo-url max-width="1280">https://78.media.tumblr.com/951e081060b3c6efc336e7ce0c332ba9/tumblr_parm2tj78a1wllbxoo1_1280.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="500">https://78.media.tumblr.com/951e081060b3c6efc336e7ce0c332ba9/tumblr_parm2tj78a1wllbxoo1_500.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="400">https://78.media.tumblr.com/951e081060b3c6efc336e7ce0c332ba9/tumblr_parm2tj78a1wllbxoo1_400.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="250">https://78.media.tumblr.com/951e081060b3c6efc336e7ce0c332ba9/tumblr_parm2tj78a1wllbxoo1_250.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="100">https://78.media.tumblr.com/951e081060b3c6efc336e7ce0c332ba9/tumblr_parm2tj78a1wllbxoo1_100.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="75">https://78.media.tumblr.com/951e081060b3c6efc336e7ce0c332ba9/tumblr_parm2tj78a1wllbxoo1_75sq.jpg</photo-url><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag></post><post id="175164783781" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/175164783781" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/175164783781/episode-sixteen-come-by-my-fire" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-06-23 07:15:12 GMT" date="Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:15:12" unix-timestamp="1529738112" format="markdown" reblog-key="TuwGxSOZ" slug="episode-sixteen-come-by-my-fire" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode Sixteen: Come By My Fire</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Syfdag, 11th of the Bear, 3206 ME&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party, still stuck in the Dissian Catacombs beneath the lake of flesh that surrounds the Iron City of Dis, were succumbing to fatigue and injury. Magnus Stairwell was caught in a mechanical stone trap that crushed his right foot, leaving it a mangled, bloody mess. Yuna was able to stabilize him so he wouldn&amp;rsquo;t bleed out, but her worsening spell sickness caused her healing spells to fail on the first attempt, and burst an uncontrolled blast of healing back onto herself on the second attempt. Despite her efforts, Magnus does not seem to be recovering, and she quickly fell exhausted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The remaining party members decided to take a breather. Still in the chamber containing the containment field that held first the green jewel that Tak used Levani to retrieve, and then Levani&amp;rsquo;s still living body once Tak made his escape. Both Magnus and Levani, she still in her discorporated form, attempted without success to take a chalk rubbing of the circular maze in the blood altar, ruining the party&amp;rsquo;s only map of the Thorimfel region in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keen tried to lift the Dragonhead coin from Levani&amp;rsquo;s unconscious body, but was foiled by Ara, who took possession of the Dragonhead, the Ring of Reduction and the Hat of True Frog from Levani&amp;rsquo;s recumbent form, for safekeeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the party sat and talked, several interesting facts were brought forth. First, the other party members could now hear Levani&amp;rsquo;s thoughts in addition to their own, even from the Ethereal plane, now that her body was freed of the magical prison that had held it suspended. Second, Magnus related the details of how he captured the djinn that had pursued them through the labyrinth, using the iron flask Ara found. Third, the party found a scrap of parchment upon which someone &amp;ndash; possibly Tak himself? &amp;ndash; had written on, trying to work out a web of relations between Tak, the party, A Tabaxi named Stalks-By-Night, and the Skink, a criminal lizardfolk organization active in the Eastriver region of Telisar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levani explored the area immediately beyond the chamber, looking for evidence of Tak&amp;rsquo;s whereabouts. She followed his tracks to a long, pitch-black passageway, as well as some seemingly empty rooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party traded stories, and through their conversation learned that Yuna and Levani had met years before, though Levani did not realize it until Yuna related the details of her upbringing. Yuna also explained her divine essence, fully revealing for the first time her aasimar nature and her true father&amp;rsquo;s angelic aspect. Yuna also revealed the details of her spell sickness, and the warning given her by Masym, Holy Mother of Syf. Levani knew something of spell sickness and further warned Yuna that left unchecked, her innate magical essence would eventually overtake and destroy her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Magnus spent some time contemplating the nature of the residium injected into him and his friends, and found that with a focus of will he could not only feel the locations of the others, but divine a sense of whether they were waking, sleeping, or in a trance. This success sparked a memory of his life before his servitude in the El Astrum Public Library, a life in which his obsession was residium and its properties. A key detail surfaced, and Magnus excitedly informed the party that residium has been long theorized to hold the key to collecting, harnessing and channeling the very essence of life and death. Magnus theorized this had something to do with necromancy, and Keen realized that it was via the residium in their systems that they all felt a stab of pain when Levani&amp;rsquo;s body took what should have been a killing blow from Tak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That Levani&amp;rsquo;s body still lived led to some speculation that perhaps the party was immortal, or that they were somehow trapping Levani&amp;rsquo;s spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levani then told of her encounter with Anansus, and with Rashtek, the lich that tried to consume her on what she thought was the Ethereal plane (though she was in fact on a plane called, by those who know of it, The Shore). Anansus, an old Dwarven god of trickery and change is widely considered to be something of a folk tale in modern Telisar, but Levani insisted the entity that saved her from Rashtek was none other. Levani also said that Anansus claimed Bahamut, the Platinum Queen and Mother of all Creation, had been slain, and charged her with recovering the pieces of Her flesh that She might be reborn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually the party decided to spend a few hours resting in the hopes that Magnus and Yuna would recover. Once everyone was in a deep sleep, Levani was surprised by the sudden appearance of a raven in the chamber. The raven seemed to be able to see Levani, even though she remained on the Ethereal Plane. It hopped about and played with her wooden owlbear statue a moment, then disappeared in a puff of feathers which dispersed into thin air. All except one, which remained, placed with purpose, in the hair of Levani&amp;rsquo;s physical body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keen was successful in lifting the Dragonhead from Ara while he remained in his trance, despite Levani&amp;rsquo;s attempt to stop him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party awoke feeling refreshed, all except Magnus, who was surprised to realize that his foot had seemingly not improved at all with rest. Worried for Magnus and puzzling over the raven feather, the party prepared to set off in search of a way out of Hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lore Status: Dumped&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Connections Revealed: Several&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RP Rating: Awesome&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag><tag>lore</tag></post><post id="175157249136" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/175157249136" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/175157249136/thorus-and-the-beggar-man" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-06-23 01:46:35 GMT" date="Fri, 22 Jun 2018 18:46:35" unix-timestamp="1529718395" format="markdown" reblog-key="KX8ViiuH" slug="thorus-and-the-beggar-man" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Thorus And The Beggar Man</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With apologies to Patrick Rothfuss&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Thorus tells it, a beggar man was walking the long road. He had nothing, neither cloak nor finery nor shoes; not one copper jot had he to his name. The Bear was well into its slumber and the frozen scrub was sharp beneath his feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The man left the road seeking shelter from the wind and the snow, when he saw the flicker of firelight in the woods. Despite his keen sense of danger, the hunger in the man&amp;rsquo;s belly drove him forward, and he approached the camp. A band of gnomes were warming themselves against a small campfire, and sharing a loaf of fresh ironbread still black from the pan.  When they saw him, they made no move to welcome him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Peace, friends,&amp;rdquo; said the beggar, &amp;ldquo;I seek only a scrap of firelight that I won&amp;rsquo;t freeze, and a sliver of food that I won&amp;rsquo;t starve.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What can you pay us?&amp;rdquo; asked a gnome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Only my gratitude,&amp;rdquo; said the man, &amp;ldquo;For the alms were poor today.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Then begone,&amp;rdquo; said the gnome, &amp;ldquo;We cannot spend gratitude.&amp;rdquo;  So the beggar man walked on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further into the woods he found a second fire, and around it a group of elves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Peace, friends,&amp;rdquo; said the beggar, &amp;ldquo;I seek only a scrap of firelight that I won&amp;rsquo;t freeze, and a sliver of food that I won&amp;rsquo;t starve.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Our horse threw a shoe. Re-shoe him and we will feed you,&amp;rdquo; said an elf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You have my sympathies, but I have not the skill to do as you ask,&amp;rdquo; said the beggar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Then begone,&amp;rdquo; said the elf, &amp;ldquo;Your sympathies won&amp;rsquo;t pull our cart.&amp;rdquo; So the beggar man walked on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now the night was on, and a hungry wind was biting. At last the beggar man saw a third fire.  Before it sat an old man, older even than the beggar. He had a heavy cloak pulled about his broad, powerful shoulders, and the flames danced in his milky eyes. To one side lay a massive broadsword, and next to it a crooked staff. The old man raised his head at the beggar&amp;rsquo;s coming, and gave him a nod.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Peace, friend,&amp;rdquo; said the beggar, &amp;ldquo;I seek only a scrap of firelight that I won&amp;rsquo;t freeze, and a sliver of food that I won&amp;rsquo;t starve. But I have nothing to pay with, and am too weak to work; indeed I have nothing offer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Have you a life?&amp;rdquo; asked the man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beggar&amp;rsquo;s wide eyes were drawn to the sword, which seemed to stare back at him, expectant. And the beggar answered &amp;ldquo;I have had a long life, friend, though the night is not done.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The old man&amp;rsquo;s eyes betrayed the briefest mirth, and he said, &amp;ldquo;Then come by my fire and drink of my ale, and for this kindness, tell me your tale.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;Thorus and The Beggar Man,&amp;rdquo; from Doranth Hammer-My-Soul-O-Moradin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Five Hundred and Twenty-Three Tales Of Moral Fortitude And Righteousness For Children Of Questionable Disposition&lt;/em&gt;, 3116 M.E.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag></post><post id="174779540221" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/174779540221" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/174779540221/a-tale-from-aras-past" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-06-11 05:54:06 GMT" date="Sun, 10 Jun 2018 22:54:06" unix-timestamp="1528696446" format="markdown" reblog-key="sWyRbYzB" slug="a-tale-from-aras-past" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>A Tale from Ara’s Past</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wodag, the 13th of the Lion, 3204 ME&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The freshly fallen leaves crunched beneath his feet on the trail while a crisp wind whistled through the treetops, bringing a promise of snow.  Animals in the forest were well along with their preparations for hibernating, and after weeks on the road, Ara knew it was probably time to seek out somewhere to see out the swift approaching winter.  While he&amp;rsquo;d spent many winters out on the road, a hay barn was way more comfortable than hard frozen ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;d never intended to be on the road this late in the year, but his head still swam with confused memories of the last town, where he&amp;rsquo;d intended to stay.  He wasn&amp;rsquo;t much of one for deep thoughts, and he knew that the consequences of many things he was aware of around him eluded him, but he couldn&amp;rsquo;t shake the feeling that there had been something not right and that he wasn&amp;rsquo;t wanted there, so he&amp;rsquo;d left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;d entered the town much the same as he usually did, drifting in in search of provisions, a bed and maybe some money. He&amp;rsquo;d been following woodland tracks that had turned into trail and on into roads that wound through farmlands on their way towards civilisation, with the ever present hope that he&amp;rsquo;d find a temple to an as yet unknown deity at the back of his mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ara, is that you?!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shout had come from a stout, swarthy looking human across the street, who&amp;rsquo;d come jogging over to eagerly greet Ara as he&amp;rsquo;d been walking past shops in search of supplies for the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;d looked vaguely familiar, but Ara couldn&amp;rsquo;t place where he&amp;rsquo;d seen him before.  &amp;ldquo;Yarp?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s me, Derenn.  Remember?  You helped me out finding the sheep that escaped my paddock, what, two, maybe three years ago now?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ara had shrugged apologetically, and leaned on his walking stick &amp;ldquo;Oh, aye, I be rememberin&amp;rsquo; that.  Not so good with the names an&amp;rsquo; faces, sorry.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh no worry, no worry.  &amp;lsquo;Tis fine, 'tis fine.  Can&amp;rsquo;t be expecting you to remember everyone you meet on your wanderings, now, can we?   So, what are you doing in Riverbend?  It&amp;rsquo;s getting well on in to Lion, you know.  Most of the crops have already been gathered, so not many farmers will be looking for much help&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, it be that late already?  I is losing track of time out in the woods.  Well, it don&amp;rsquo;t matter, whatever people be needing in exchange for lodgings, I&amp;rsquo;m sure I can be doing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, if'n you don&amp;rsquo;t mind spending a few nights at my homestead, there&amp;rsquo;s use for at least one more pair of hands around the farm, help me get everything all set for winter.  I can probably see my way to giving you a little bit of gold for your trouble too.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ara paused and shifted his pack further up his shoulders.  &amp;ldquo;Sure, I be thinking I can do that for ya, no problem.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Settled in the back of a cart, riding with Derenn, he&amp;rsquo;d noticed the people of Riverbend had seemed to be walking with some haste, glancing around them.  Very few were stopping to talk.  What they had with them, they held close, hugged to their chests.  Town folk had always seem to be strange to Ara, though, and he&amp;rsquo;d soon given up thinking about it.  He wasn&amp;rsquo;t in Riverbend often enough to know if it was unusual or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the ride Derenn had explained to Ara about stuff happening in the town.  Something involving lizards setting and enforcing rules, and being paid for it?  None of it had made that much sense to him. How could lizards be in charge of anything, let alone enforce rules?  They&amp;rsquo;re so small you could probably step on them without a thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a week on the farm, all had been fine.  There had been animals to muck out, hay to stack in the barns, fresh bedding to lay down and the like, as the farm had started preparing for winter.&lt;br/&gt;
It was hard work, preparing the farm for winter, but also work that needed doing.  Ara liked to help out wherever he could, and enjoyed working with his hands, there was something comforting about the repetition of movement, and it always gave him time to think.  As was often the case, his thoughts went towards faith, and the edicts.  He didn&amp;rsquo;t really understand a huge amount about the his faith, nor pretty much any others he&amp;rsquo;d read about, but they almost all encouraged helping other people.
Ara had willingly set to work alongside Manaren, Derenn&amp;rsquo;s youngest child.  Manaren had none of Derenn&amp;rsquo;s stoutness, taking more after his mother.  One the second day, Manaren had joined in with Ara as he went through his morning exercises including going through a simple set of katas, sequences of moves based around his walking stick, designed to stretch out muscles and keep him limber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;d been there just over a week when things started to go strange.  Manaren hadn&amp;rsquo;t been helping that day, and Ara had assumed he was working elsewhere on the farm, but when dinner time had come around, Manaren had still been nowhere to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I be thinking I no be seeing your youngest today.. Mano.. Mana.. Manera?  He okay?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Manaren?  I dunno.. those Stormlizard boys from town, they came around early this morning and took him with them.  Not a good group, them, let me tell you.  Thinking they can go around and take what they want, hurt who they like just because they&amp;rsquo;re Skinks&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You be sayin&amp;rsquo; they took 'im?  That just ain&amp;rsquo;t right.  I be seeing about that&amp;rdquo;  Ara had hurriedly pushed away from the table, and grabbing his walking stick and cloak on the way to the door.  In the background he&amp;rsquo;d heard the sound of a chair falling as Derenn had swiftly stood up, and called out but Ara hadn&amp;rsquo;t stopped.  Maybe things would have been better if he had?  As far as Ara was concerned, some things couldn&amp;rsquo;t be tolerated, and kidnapping was one of them.  You don&amp;rsquo;t take things that aren&amp;rsquo;t yours.   After all, as the holy books said &amp;ldquo;A bird in the hand is worth three gnomes and a half-elf.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hood up, walking stick in hand, he&amp;rsquo;d swiftly returned to Riverbend, keeping a careful watch ahead of his feet for the lizards Derenn had been talking about, but not seeing any.  He&amp;rsquo;d had days to ponder the lizard problem in Riverbend, but still hadn&amp;rsquo;t made head nor tails of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On arriving in the town, all had been strangely still and quiet.  He&amp;rsquo;d noticed that almost every town and village had at least one drunk person stumbling around at night.  Although the monks at the temple he&amp;rsquo;d been raised in brewed and drank beer, he&amp;rsquo;d never really enjoyed the feeling of being drunk.  It had always seemed strange to him that some people wanted to just drink and drink until they fell asleep, but as long as they didn&amp;rsquo;t hurt anyone else he didn&amp;rsquo;t see harm in it.   Riverbend had seemed to be lacking them, however, and it hadn&amp;rsquo;t been obvious why.  There hadn’t even been any signs of lights in any of the houses he&amp;rsquo;d passed either, though it had still been relatively early evening.  Maybe people couldn&amp;rsquo;t get hold of candles?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually as he&amp;rsquo;d walked along the streets, he&amp;rsquo;d seen what had seemed to be a torch lit up ahead and he&amp;rsquo;d gone towards it, calling out as he’d stepped in to the light it cast.  &amp;ldquo;Evening!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What the hell?&amp;rdquo;  The holder of the torch dropped it in his surprise, and the friends with him had swiftly drawn their swords half out of their scabbards.  Ara sighed and dropped his hood.  He&amp;rsquo;d forgotten that people seemed to have problems seeing him when he had his hood up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sorry, sorry, I no be meaning to surprise you.  I just be wondering where everyone is?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The torch bearer had picked the torch back up again, but his companions had kept their swords drawn, points held sloppily, causing Ara to frown.  Like many wood elves, he&amp;rsquo;d been trained to use swords from an early age, and his teachers would have given him extra chores at the temple if he&amp;rsquo;d shown such poor form.  Whoever had trained them had done a poor job.  Worse, the swords hadn&amp;rsquo;t been kept in a good state, nicks and notches that should have been dealt with marring their surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Where everyone is?  They&amp;rsquo;d better be in their beds if they know what&amp;rsquo;s good for them&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In their beds?  It still be early!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes, in their beds&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s past curfew.  Speaking of which, why aren&amp;rsquo;t you in bed?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Curfew? There&amp;rsquo;s a curfew 'ere?  I no be 'earing about that.  I just be looking for, umm&amp;hellip; Mano.. Mana.. Manera I think it be?&amp;rdquo;
The torch bearer&amp;rsquo;s companions had started to surround Ara, and that had made him slightly concerned and confused.  There hadn&amp;rsquo;t been any reason for them to do that, and so he&amp;rsquo;d cautiously adjusted his grip on his walking stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Manera?  I don&amp;rsquo;t know a &amp;hellip; oh wait, you mean Manaren.  He&amp;rsquo;s off with the boss.  Not that it&amp;rsquo;s any of your business.  If you don&amp;rsquo;t go back to your home, now, we&amp;rsquo;ll have to give you a painful lesson.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I no be wanting that.  I just be wanting Manaren.  I not be understanding why you be making such a fuss about it.  Don&amp;rsquo;t the good books say 'You do not need the name of a river to cross it?’&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ummm&amp;hellip; probably?  Anyway, yes, I heard you the first time.  You want Manaren.  I told you, he&amp;rsquo;s seeing the boss.  You won&amp;rsquo;t be seeing him tonight.  So Go. Home. Now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, no, no, no, I no be doing that.  I be needing to get Manaren.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, you can&amp;rsquo;t say I didn&amp;rsquo;t warn you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that, the sword bearers had attacked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With honed skills and instincts born out of decades of practice and training, Ara had dropped in to a defensive stance and easily brushed past the sloppy attack from the first swordsman, breaking their wrist with a swift retaliatory snap of the walking stick.
&amp;ldquo;Stop! I no be&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; He&amp;rsquo;d started to call out, but had been forced to stop as another sword was swung towards his head.  Pivoting around his stick he&amp;rsquo;d avoided the sword strike, and taken another one down with a kick to the head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However they&amp;rsquo;d learned to fight, they seemed entirely inept.  Their movements were big, easy to read, and really easy for Ara avoid.  It had also left them wide open for a counter hit.  He&amp;rsquo;d soon disarmed them all easily, leaving most either unconscious, or nursing broken or badly bruised limbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, I no be wanting to do that, but you be trying to hit me, and I can&amp;rsquo;t be letting you do that&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Ara had approached him, the torchbearer had scrambled backwards, nursing an arm, whimpering as he got to his feet.  &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know who you are, but you&amp;rsquo;ll be sorry.  Boss ain&amp;rsquo;t gonna like this, Boss ain&amp;rsquo;t gonna like this one bit.  I&amp;rsquo;m gonna go tell him about you, you&amp;rsquo;ll be sorry.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;d taken off at a sprint before Ara could say anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ara had followed, wanting to at least improvise a sling for the torchbearer, but he failed to catch up before they had disappeared in to tavern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;d barely got one foot through the door of the inn, before he heard the torchbearer scream &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s him, that&amp;rsquo;s the one.  He&amp;rsquo;s the one who beat up the gang and broke my arm!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next fight had gone just about as well as the first fight.  Big movements, easily avoided, all over and done with before he&amp;rsquo;d even taken a dozen breaths.  The torchbearer had scrambled up the staircase, tears falling from his face.  &amp;ldquo;Boss! Boss! Boss!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The smell of blood and sweat had come to Ara as he&amp;rsquo;d opened the door to the back room, mixed with something else Ara didn&amp;rsquo;t recognise.  Sitting behind a large desk ahead of him had sat a young man, methodically polishing a simple, functional looking sword.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hmmm. So you&amp;rsquo;d be the four armed evil drow with a magically duplicating quarterstaff that Ramiren was telling me about?  The one that has beaten up all of my men?&amp;rdquo;
Then off to one side, &amp;ldquo;Ramiren, you&amp;rsquo;re an idiot.  That&amp;hellip; thing&amp;hellip; is a wood elf. That quarterstaff looks pretty basic to me, barely more than a tree branch.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The young man had paused, looking Ara up and down with a faint look of disgust, before continuing, &amp;ldquo;Congratulations, elf, though I&amp;rsquo;m sure they were no challenge.  It&amp;rsquo;s not like they actually know what to do with those swords, despite what they think.  Good enough for scaring your typical farmer, or the feeble fools that live in this town&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pacing forwards Ara had approached the edge of the desk.  &amp;ldquo;Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Ara Am Akiir, nice to meet you.  I be 'ere to get Manuel.  You be taking 'im, I be taking 'im back&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh look Ramiren, you&amp;rsquo;re in good company.  It&amp;rsquo;s another idiot.  Ara, my name is Shaornen, and I&amp;rsquo;m your worst nightmare.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ara paused, confused. &amp;ldquo;No, you don&amp;rsquo;t look like my worst nightmare.  No wings, and your jaw ain&amp;rsquo;t big enough.  I be pretty sure you ain&amp;rsquo;t a dragon&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Okaaaaaaay.  Anyway, you&amp;rsquo;re here for Manaren, I believe.  Thing is, we didn&amp;rsquo;t take him.  He came by choice.  He&amp;rsquo;s one of us, a Stormlizard. Aren&amp;rsquo;t you, Manaren?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind Shaornen, a door had opened and Manaren had stepped through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s true, Ara.  I came by choice, just like I told my father.&amp;rdquo;  Mararen had shuffled his feet, avoiding Ara&amp;rsquo;s gaze.  &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m tired of life on a farm.  I saw a chance of making something more of myself and I took it.  I joined the Stormlizards.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, I be pretty sure your father be telling me you were taken by them, and I can&amp;rsquo;t be letting that happen.  I be setting you free, by force if I have to&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shaornen had stood up slowly.  &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t think you heard him.  He&amp;rsquo;s here of his own choice.  I can&amp;rsquo;t let you take him, so just turn around and go back to his father and remind him of the happy news that his son has abandoned him.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, I be pretty sure his father said you took him.  I can&amp;rsquo;t let you be doing that.  Manaren, I be needing you to come with me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well, okay then elf.  I guess we do this the hard way&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHUMPH&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ara had fallen back, dropping his walking stick, reeling as the desk that had been between him and Shaornen crashed into him, tossed by a quick kick by Shaornen.
He&amp;rsquo;d barely got back to his feet before he found himself face to face with Shaornen, sword in hand, point held low.  Unlike everyone else he&amp;rsquo;d fought today, Shaornen clearly knew what he was doing, and Ara knew he was going to regret not having kept hold of his stick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearing his mind of thought, Ara had settled in to a defensive stance, feet planted, allowing his instincts to dictate his actions.  The speed of the first attack from Shaornen had still taken him by surprise. It had been a quick slash across the body, and while he&amp;rsquo;d dodged and avoided the worst of the damage, the sword had still caught him across the shoulder.  The cut had burned like fire, providing focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the next blow had come, he dove for the ground, rolling under the blade and returning to his feet, walking stick in hand, coming face to face with Manaren making a clumsy attempt at a strike on him with a broom.  Ara had parried and feeling like he&amp;rsquo;d had no choice, countered with a blow to the side of Manaren&amp;rsquo;s head, dropping him to the floor unconscious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fight with Shaornen had been fairly evenly balanced.  With the fall of Manaren, Shaornen had moved in on the offensive, barely giving Ara a chance to do anything other than dodge or parry, as attack had followed attack in a smooth sequence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flaw, when he had spotted it, had taken him by surprise.  With every third swing, as Shaornen had moved forwards with the blow, he tended to over-extend himself just a little.  As the next sequence had started, Ara had counted the swings, one, two and then with the third, stepped to the side, grabbing the over-extended arm with his off-hand, pulling just enough to send Shaornen stumbling forwards.  As Shaornen had stumbled forwards, Ara had followed through with a swift blow to the back of the head and spun, swinging his stick around and up into the jaw, meeting it on Shaornen&amp;rsquo;s way down.
The force of the blow, along with the angle of the impact, had broken Shaornen’s neck, killing him before he&amp;rsquo;d even hit the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I be sorry, friend, I no be wanting to do that, but you don&amp;rsquo;t be leaving me any choice.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing the death of Shaornen, and Manaren unconscious on the floor, Ramiren had taken one look at Ara and fled, holding his broken arm close to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As he&amp;rsquo;d fled, Ramiren had shouted out &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ll regret this Ara.  When the Skinks find out about this, there will be consequences&amp;rdquo;.  The reference to lizards had just confused Ara some more.  There&amp;rsquo;s no way lizards would be any threat to anyone, and why would they care about any human dying?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Binding up the various cuts he&amp;rsquo;d received, he&amp;rsquo;d grabbed the unconscious Manaren, slung him over his shoulders and set off for the farm.  He&amp;rsquo;d barely gone far before he&amp;rsquo;d run in to Derenn with his wagon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ara?  That you?  Manaren!?  What happened to him?!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ara carefully laid Manaren down in the &amp;ldquo;I be sorry, but they be taking him and confusing him.  He be starting to think he chose to go, not that he was taken.  He kind of left me no choice when he attacked me.  I no be meaning to hurt him.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, no, no. He did choose to go.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t mean they kidnapped him.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staring in horror behind Ara, Derren had spotted the unconscious bodies of the swordsmen Ara had attacked earlier, letting out a groan. &amp;ldquo;Oh, Syf, no&amp;hellip; what did you do?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I no be sure I understand.  Taking is taking.&amp;rdquo;  Realising he was talking about the people he&amp;rsquo;d dealt with earlier, &amp;ldquo;Oh that?  I not be sure.  I be talking to them about Miguel, an&amp;rsquo; all of a sudden they be trying to hit me their swords.  I tried not to hit 'em too hard&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh no, you idiot.  The Skinks are going to find out.  They&amp;rsquo;ll come out in force to deal with us.  There will be no peace now for Riverbend.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People had started to come out of the surrounding houses, drawn by the sound of shouting.  Once they saw the unconscious bodies, more voices had joined in with Derenn, sounding terrified and scared, staring at Ara.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confused, tired, bewildered how doing the right thing had seemingly been the wrong thing, Ara had hitched up his backpack, walking stick in hand, and fled, heading towards the nearest forest and the peace he always found there.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>lore</tag><tag>ara</tag><tag>player-authored</tag></post><post id="174491978286" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/174491978286" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/174491978286/episode-fifteen-three-druids-an-eye-and-a-voice" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-06-02 07:14:16 GMT" date="Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:14:16" unix-timestamp="1527923656" format="markdown" reblog-key="EtK7fVf0" slug="episode-fifteen-three-druids-an-eye-and-a-voice" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode Fifteen: Three Druids, An Eye and A Voice: A Tale of Goblins</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wodag, 8th of the Shark, 3206 ME&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Black Tack tribe led a typical Goblin existence, worrying caravans of big folk on the roads, hunting game upon the back sof Wargs, and making war with the other tribes in the hills of Thorimfel. That is until a roving band of adventurers discovered their cavernous home and laid waste to it, slaying half the tribe and chasing out the rest. Some span of days later, the survivors, bereft of their king, their treasure and their home, were scavenging to survive in the dangerous wastes of the Stone Forest, a large forest of petrified stone trees that had stood in those hills for an age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three druids, Skaggit, Skaarsgaard, and Skaggark, and their ranger companion The Eye Of Kikka Lenna were among the survivors. Miserable already, Skaggit was overcome with the loss of his beloved trash pile and his roach companion, Scrubby, and decided to make the journey back to the abandoned caverns. Their positions in the power vacuum of the leaderless tribe tenuous, the others elected to follow; Skaggark thought he might find and claim the elders&amp;rsquo; horde of special berries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together they made the dangerous trek through the Stone Forest, relying on stealth, wild shapes and the ranger&amp;rsquo;s natural survival instincts. They mostly succeeded in avoiding the attentions of the beasts that live there, but for a large Black Bear that Skaggark antagonised. Having dispatched the Bear, the goblins made their way to the edge of the treeline and discovered the mouth of the lair&amp;rsquo;s cave entrance had been collapsed, no doubt by those meddling adventurers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeking another way in they tried, unsuccessfully, to bargain with a turkey vulture for assistance, before nearly being discovered by a Roc &amp;ndash; a monstrous bird-fiend that despite its keen senses failed to detect the stealthy goblins as they scrambled for cover in the stone trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was at this point Skaggark, in the form of a sinuous panther, discovered they had been followed by Skoom, a bullying brute of a goblin, formerly one of the Black tack&amp;rsquo;s cooks and minders of goblits. Staying hidden, they evaded Skoom&amp;rsquo;s notice, and he passed through them carrying the large oak branch he favoured as a cudgel. Once he scaled the cliff face and disappeared over the top, they stealthily followed him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skoom unknowingly led the goblins up the side of the cliff to a small passage through the rock and into a section of the caverns none of them had ever been in. Thinking this must be the elder goblins&amp;rsquo; secret back entrance they followed, eventually finding not their erstwhile home but a passageway that ended in the ceiling of a large empty room of Deurgar construction. Bruised and battered from falls and traps, the goblins rested briefly before continuing, only to encounter Skoom held fast by a strange force, standing motionless a short distance away in a passageway. The Eye quickly realized a gelatinous cube stood before them, slowly consuming the engulfed Skoom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goblins did battle, wisely keeping their distance and harrying the cube with webs of a giant spider. They damaged the monstrosity enough to make their escape, and as they fled they quickly investigated the discarded corpse of Skoom, and found he clutched a strange blue crystal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as the Eye picked up the crystal a vile, black Voice thundered in their minds, demanding servitude, and promising riches in return for obedience. The Eye attempted to resist the command of the Voice and promptly exploded, his body covering the walls, ceiling and floor of the passwageway in gore. The remaining goblins quickly swore their allegiance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Voice directed them further down into the structure, to a large meeting hall, wherein they found a massive quantity of blue crystal jutting out of the ground, pushing aside the dwarven masonry as it grew. The Voice commanded the goblins to return to their tribe, to lead them here, to do its bidding. It would teach them to harvest the crystal, to sew it into their flesh, and be granted power and wealth beyond goblin reckoning. In return they were to seek out four individuals &amp;ndash; the Dragon, the Flame, the Seeker, and the Man Who Did Not Die. They were to capture them and deliver them to a place of the Voice&amp;rsquo;s choosing, a task to which the remaining goblins readily agreed, the blood still trickling from their ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monstrosities Avoided: 2 of 3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trash Heaps Recovered: 0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plot Hooks Revealed: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goblin RP Rating: Awesome!&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag><tag>oneshot</tag></post><post id="174315832576" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/174315832576" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/174315832576/anansus-and-gruumsh-and-the-coming-of-the-elves" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-05-27 22:10:42 GMT" date="Sun, 27 May 2018 15:10:42" unix-timestamp="1527459042" format="markdown" reblog-key="rlxcwClK" slug="anansus-and-gruumsh-and-the-coming-of-the-elves" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Anansus and Gruumsh, and the Coming of the Elves</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Too ebulliant for the Sisterhood, and too chaotic for the Five, Anansus was ever apart from the
elder gods. She (when she decided she was a she) cavorted and danced through all of creation,
existing here as a flock of birds &amp;ndash; she loves ravens best &amp;ndash; and there as a lightning storm raging
across the sky; now a golden tortoise, or a twinkle of light from the Evening Star, or the sigh
of your lover&amp;rsquo;s last kiss.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Papum, I&amp;rsquo;m only eight.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hush. And he (when he decided he was a he) delighted in teasing the gods, playing merry pranks. Did
you know he once turned every one of Thorus&amp;rsquo;s scales into fish, and set them loose in the Bay Of
Clearfrost? Hah! The Five scolded Anansus that day (though not before laughing at their brother
splashing about with an armful of bluebellies, naked and shivering). And though they scolded
Anansus he never learned, for Anansus is ever a child, and hubris is his nature.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You were going to tell me about the Elves, Papum.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t interrupt! Stories are like a river; you must&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let them flow were they will, for they know their way. I &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt;, Papum.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hmph. So one day, old Anansus, he saw Gruumsh, the Orc-god, hunting a great boar in the forest.
&amp;lsquo;Here is some sport!&amp;rsquo; he thought to himself, and when Gruumsh had lost sight of it for a moment,
Anansus changed the boar into a tuskberry bush &amp;ndash; the first tuskberry bush, in fact, which is why to
this day we&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Papum!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alright, alright, peace. so Anansus, he makes himself into a wild boar just like the one Gruumsh
was hunting. And he leads poor Gruumsh on a merry chase through the forest for a hundred years.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s ridiculous.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, so you know this story, do you? How about you finish it, then? Hmm?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hmph. So Gruumsh tracks Anansus for a hundred years, until his belly is so empty, and his legs are
so tired he throws down his spear, Itk'sha, and howls in rage. Seeing this, Anansus appears before
him in her true form, laughing and dancing. 'I won! I won! A hundred years and you could never catch
me, Gruumsh.&amp;rsquo; And she became the wind and danced away, laughing all the while.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is that why in Elvish Anansus is called Corellon Larethian, Papum? The Laughing Wind?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re too clever by half. Hush. But Gruumsh, he was furious, and so he picked up Itk'sha and
followed Anansus, stealthy as a grass rat, silent as rage. And wherever Anansus went, Gruumsh would
spring out from behind a rock, or leap from a tree, or rise from the river and attack Anansus,
hurtling his mighty spear. And should Itk'sha ever find its mark, Anansus would screech
with pain and disappear, cursing Gruumsh and swearing revenge. But Anansus is too changing to keep
to a blood oath, and soon enough would forget, and be drawn back to Telisar by one thing or another.
And there Gruumsh would be again, and there was the barbed hook of Ituk'sha.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The &lt;em&gt;Elves&lt;/em&gt;, Papum.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;So for an age, Gruumsh would ambush Anansus wherever he appeared, and wherever Itk'sha struck true,
a drop of Anansus&amp;rsquo;s blood would touch the earth. And from that blood rose the Seldarine, the first
of the Elves.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Finally!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the forest rose Rillifane; in the sea, Deep Sashelas; in the mountain tops, Aerdrie
Faenya; and all their brother/sisters. And to each of the Seldarine was granted a full measure of
divinity, for they were of Anansus himself. And like Anansus, these first Elves were ever-changing,
as mercurial as Corellon, as they called him&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I knew it!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;ndash;and as full of joy. For a time the Seldarine made their homes here, on Telisar, and held dominion
over the sea and forest and the desert and the air, and they sired all the races of Elves. This was
long ago, of course, before the coming of Lolth and her Drow. But that is another story, and the
hour grows late.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Wasn&amp;rsquo;t Lolth an elf too? At first I mean?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;She was. And perhaps tomorrow I will tell you that tale. For the tale of Lolth and Corellon, and
the dividing of the Seldarine, that is a tale of woe and warning.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Did Anansus ever escape from Gruumsh?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He did! Anansus tricked him into turning his great spear Itk'sha into a snake, and the snake put
out Gruumsh&amp;rsquo;s eye. And as the blood flowed from his ruined eye socket, thick and hot and black, it
splashed upon the ground and from it the race of Orcs were born. And with the coming of the Orcs,
the Seldarine &amp;ndash; ah, but it is time for rest.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Papum!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Peace, Tiny Blossom. The fire is but embers. Rest now.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Very well. I love you, Papa Banu.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And I you, Granddaughter.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag></post><post id="174043418906" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/174043418906" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/174043418906/episode-fourteen-reap-the-whirlwind" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-05-19 07:24:53 GMT" date="Sat, 19 May 2018 00:24:53" unix-timestamp="1526714693" format="markdown" reblog-key="DJmV77t7" slug="episode-fourteen-reap-the-whirlwind" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode Fourteen: Reap The Whirlwind</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Syfdag, 11th of the Bear, 3206 ME&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still far underground in the Dissian Catacombs searching for Levani&amp;rsquo;s body, the party took a brief rest after their encounter with a mimic. They rummaged through the monstrosity&amp;rsquo;s small horde of treasure, taking a sizable stash of gold coins, and a large, heavy iron padlock and key. Yuna picked up a cloak that seemed to flutter of its own accord, but the party left behind a potion of flying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refreshed after their rest, the party was faced with an impenetrable set of metal doors blocking their way forward. Several attempts were made to dislodge or open them without success. At last, Yuna and Magnus discovered a large crank buried in the sand pit in the middle of the chamber. Turning the crank unlocked the doors; as they stepped through the party found themselves in a labyrinth. Their presence  awoke a djinn, who conjured a whirlwind and created a massive swirling storm of sand, thunder and lightning. With the whirlwind in pursuit, the party raced through the maze, doing their best to dodge traps and obstructions and not get lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowed by a collapsed wall and confused by the maze, Yuna was consumed by the whirlwind; thus trapped and unable to break free the lightning nearly killed her, and it was only through her use of healing spells that she was able to withstand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also unable to outrun the whirlwind, Magnus turned to face it, and was able to land one strike on the djinn before being swept up and carried aloft in the storm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ara, Keen and the discorporated Levani made their way through the maze, but were beset by sand mephits, which rose up out of the ground to attack the party. The devils were quickly dispatched, and Ara found a large iron flask in the arms of a skeleton, whose bones had been picked clean by a swarm of insects. He tried opening the flask, but to no effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magnus broke free of the whirlwind and was able to catch up to the rest of the party. Seeing the flask, he realized it was meant to hold a creature prisoner and bind it to one&amp;rsquo;s will. He opened the flask and with an effort of will bound the djinn to it, sucking the creature into the flask. Thus the whirlwind was dispelled and Yuna saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bruised, beaten and exhausted, the party risked a long rest before continuing deeper into the Catacombs. Leaving the labyrinth behind, they soon came upon a section of passageways Levani had visited before in her fateful encounter with Tak, the treacherous bard who first summoned her to Dis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party was briefly slowed by attempting to navigate a pit filled with acidic green goo, but thanks to Yuna manifesting her angel wings and Ara and Keen&amp;rsquo;s impromptu tumbling and parkour act, they were able to overcome it. Retracing her steps, Levani led the party to the very spot where Tak had sacrificed her to release a large gem from a magical enclosure. But instead of a gem, now it was Levanni&amp;rsquo;s still-living body that was trapped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In gaining entrance to this final chamber, Magnus was caught in a mechanical wall puzzle and his ankle was crushed between slabs of stone. Keen was able to free him but not before Magnus sustained a serious injury. Using a few drops of blood from his mangled foot, Magnus dispelled the magic of the enclosure by activating the sacrifical altar, and released Levanni&amp;rsquo;s body, which fell to the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was the enclosure sustaining her body? In releasing the body from its prison has the party doomed Levanni to an eternity on the Ethereal Plane? Will they ever find Tak? And how will they escape from Hell?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experimental Mini-Game Rating: Pretty not bad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Owlbear Pantomime Performance Rating: Inscrutable&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Djinns in a Bottle: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long-Term Injuries Sustained: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levannis Recovered: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RP Rating: Awesome&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag></post><post id="173841951471" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/173841951471" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/173841951471/labyrinth" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-05-12 23:05:41 GMT" date="Sat, 12 May 2018 16:05:41" unix-timestamp="1526166341" format="markdown" reblog-key="RTuGXKVf" slug="labyrinth" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Labyrinth!</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;Your presence has awakened the defenses of the Dissian Catacombs. Between you and safety lies a
deadly labyrinth, full of monsters, dead ends, traps, obstructions and secret passages. But you have
no time for caution -– a djinn is pursuing you in a whirlwind of sand, thunder and lightning. Each of you must successfully reach the exit 500ft away 
without being caught, or risk death fighting your way free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chase is resolved in
initiative order, but the party may choose this order at the start of the labyrinth; the party&amp;rsquo;s pursuers will go last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On your turn, you must RESOLVE ENCOUNTERS, NAVIGATE, and MOVE. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet escaped, you must now roll for an EVENT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RESOLVE ENCOUNTERS.&lt;/strong&gt; You may find yourself engaged in combat while racing through the maze. If
so, you must resolve the combat encounter before you can continue, either by defeating or
incapacitating your enemies or by disengaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NAVIGATION.&lt;/strong&gt; Make a WIS check to determine which way to go. The DC for NAVIGATION checks starts at
15; each successful check lowers the DC by one for the next party member (to a minimum of 10). Each
failure raises the DC by 1 (to a maximum of 20). You can substitute any skill in which you are
proficient provided you can justify how it helps you navigate the maze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MOVE.&lt;/strong&gt; If you succeeded your NAVIGATION check, take up to your full movement plus your DASH towards the exit. Subtract this amount from 500; if your distance from the exit reaches zero, you have escaped!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVENTS.&lt;/strong&gt; Roll a d8 on the EVENT Table and resolve it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter.&lt;/strong&gt; Begin your next turn in combat (DM will specify the enemy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encounter.&lt;/strong&gt; Begin your next turn in combat (DM will specify the enemy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Obstruction.&lt;/strong&gt; Make a DC 12 STR (Athletics or Acrobatics) saving throw or move in difficult terrain on your next turn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drop An Item.&lt;/strong&gt; Make a DC 12 WIS saving throw to see if you notice what you drop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hazard.&lt;/strong&gt; Make a DC 12 DEX saving throw or take damage (DM will roll)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trip.&lt;/strong&gt; Make a DC 12 DEX saving throw or start your next turn prone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No EVENT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ACT.&lt;/strong&gt; If you successfully resolved your EVENT (ie, rolled a 3, 4, 5 or 6 and succeeded in your saving throw, or rolled a 7 or 8), you now have 3 seconds to announce an action you wish to take, if any. This can be any action you would normally be capable of in initiative order, or one of the following special assists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check for clues.&lt;/strong&gt; Make a DC12 INT (Investigation) check (or substitute any appropriate
proficiency, at the DM&amp;rsquo;s discretion).  On success, lower the DC of the NAVIGATION check by 1 (to a minimum of 10)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find a shortcut.&lt;/strong&gt; Make a DC12 INT (Investigation) check (or substitute any appropriate
proficiency, at the DM&amp;rsquo;s discretion). On success, all party members move an extra 100 feet closer to
the exit on their next successful NAVIGATION check.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GETTING CAUGHT.&lt;/strong&gt; The djinn will move on its turn towards the party. If it gets to within 30ft of any party member, they are now in combat and must resolve the encounter before continuing.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>minigame</tag><tag>homebrew</tag></post><post id="173599709326" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/173599709326" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/173599709326/episode-thirteen-the-reticulated-glowing-wooden" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-05-05 06:50:30 GMT" date="Fri, 04 May 2018 23:50:30" unix-timestamp="1525503030" format="markdown" reblog-key="Q57zaCPB" slug="episode-thirteen-the-reticulated-glowing-wooden" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode Thirteen: The Reticulated Glowing Wooden Owlbear and the Mimic</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Freydag, 10th of the Bear, 3206 ME (continued)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Levani&amp;rsquo;s floating owl bear leading the way, the party descended deep into the catacombs under the Iron City of Dis, in an attempt to recover Levani&amp;rsquo;s body and restore her soul. They found themselves moving through a series of traps and puzzle rooms. Magnus, having noticed some thieves cant on the wall, inadvertently triggered one such trap, and the party was thrown down shafts into a pit full of undead, from which ghastly, ghoulish hands rose up and attempted to pull them under, tearing and rending. The mass of undead was held at bay by the party&amp;rsquo;s cleric, Yuna, while Levani&amp;rsquo;s discorporated spirit on the ethereal plane harnessed the power of the Schipuk ur Flasch (&amp;ldquo;Burning Spirit&amp;rdquo;), an element of her blood curse, and set them ablaze. The remaining undead were dispatched by Magnus, Ara and Keen. 
During the fight Keen realized his new blade, the Punisher, was capable of inflicting psychic damage on its targets if it heard a pun at the moment of striking. This led to pointed attempts to pierce the veil of comedy, with rapier wit and cunning ripostes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party escaped the pit of undead (which revealed Yuna&amp;rsquo;s angelic wings to Magnus for the first time) only to find themselves in a locked room, with their desired exit blocked by metal doors barred on the opposite side. Levani once again harnessed her ethereal powers to whip a sizable quantity of sand into a spinning buzzsaw blade and cut most of the way through the wooden timber barring the doors, which Magnus was then able to break through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was then that Keen, enticed by the promise of riches, tried to pick the lock on a mimic. The party vanquished the foe, but as they stood catching their breath Ara and Keen could hear a low buzzing noise from the next room, the sound of thousands and thousands of insects, growing steadily louder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Puns Delivered: One and a half, maybe&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mimics: It wasn&amp;rsquo;t even trying, I mean, a treasure chest?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rules the DM forgot: Oh gods, the dodge action after turn undead, the homebrew spell sickness that should have had the cleric at 1 point of exhaustion the whole time, the swarm of corpses was supposed to have multiattack, I mean what didn&amp;rsquo;t I forget more like, amirite?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reticulating Glowing Wooden Owl Bear Communique Rating: Surprisingly nuanced&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RPing: Awesome&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag></post><post id="173160721831" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/173160721831" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/173160721831/episode-twelve-the-shield-of-whitebridge" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-04-21 15:35:48 GMT" date="Sat, 21 Apr 2018 08:35:48" unix-timestamp="1524324948" format="markdown" reblog-key="8Zzd3Oiv" slug="episode-twelve-the-shield-of-whitebridge" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode Twelve: The Shield of Whitebridge</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Freydag, 10th of the Bear, 3206 ME (continued)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morning in Whitebridge brought the party a much-needed rest. During his meditation, however, Ara dreamt of an encounter with Aleh Xa Akiir, an eldery elven woman who claimed to be both his ancestor and childhood friend, from a city &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; called Akiir. The city was the ancient home of Elves on Telisar, or so she claimed, and was destroyed in the Cataclysm Of Ice, long ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aleh Xa told Ara his &amp;ldquo;holy quest&amp;rdquo; was more important now than ever, and that he must &amp;ldquo;reunite the Five-Fold Path of the Akiiri Fist.&amp;rdquo; The five Fists are hidden somewhere in Telisar; Ara is to seek them out. The first is the Fist Of The North Wind. Ara and Aleh Xa sparred in the dream, and in the end Aleh Xa decided to accompany Ara in his quest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awakening from his meditative trance, Ara found his walking stick now had a wisp of blue energy around one end, and is possessed by the spirit of Aleh Xa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party left the Hanged Man&amp;rsquo;s Wink, whereupon Ara was mobbed by residents of the town, who praised him for standing down the Bone Devil, calling him Master Ara and The Shield Of Whitebridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keen stole a corn muffin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The procession proceeded through town to Anthol&amp;rsquo;s Amazing Arcana. In gratitude for saving Anthol the Younger from the fairy ring, Anthol the Elder allowed the party to take their pick of the many wonderous artifacts he had collected over a lifetime of adventuring. Keen selected a rapier called the Punisher, a slightly longer than standard rapier with a guard of spun steel in the shape of a grinning troll face. Yuna selected a shirt of mithril chain with cold-resistance properties. Magnus finally replaced his axes with a matched pair of silvered throwing hatchetts. Levani, looking for something to help her communicate in the material world, found a carved wooden owlbear toy with posable ears, eyebrows and mouth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nicely equipped, the party next led Banu to the outskirts of town, to the very spot Levani had been summoned to the Nine Hells. Banu opened a portal using the residual magical energies of the summoning circle, but the portal was unstable, and instead of arriving at the spot where Levani found herself when summoned by Tak, the party was dropped into the blistering red sands of the plains outside the Iron City of Dis. Unsure of where they were, but sure of the location of Levani&amp;rsquo;s body thanks to their psychic link, the party began walking towards the city. Near the shores of the horrific lake of liquid flesh from which the city emerges, Levani&amp;rsquo;s spirit found a staircase that led hundreds of feet down into the darkness. The staircase ended in a labyrinth of catacombs that extend far under the lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paths Of the Akiiri Fist: 5, apparently&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wooden Owlbear Surrogates: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lake Of Lemures: Gross&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RP Rating: Awesome&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>session</tag><tag>dnd</tag></post><post id="172817597321" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/172817597321" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/172817597321/on-the-subject-of-tieflings" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-04-11 05:26:05 GMT" date="Tue, 10 Apr 2018 22:26:05" unix-timestamp="1523424365" format="markdown" reblog-key="otMHWKXB" slug="on-the-subject-of-tieflings" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>On The Subject of Tieflings</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;excerpted from Pheseis Eternal&amp;rsquo;s Remarks To the Arcanus Assembly, El Astrum Public Library, 2752 M.E.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is said that all Tieflings can trace their ancestry back to Asmodeus, the god of sin, and Supreme Master of the Nine Hells. Intoxicated by the promise of powers beyond their imagining, these earliest human descendants made a pact with the archdevil. In return, his blood was infused with their own and the Tiefling bloodline was born.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the Tieflings spread through mortal realms, they enthralled the “lesser folk,” performing “miracles” and dispersing the “wisdom” of their masters. It wasn’t uncommon for Tieflings to seduce and interbreed with other races, and it was quickly discovered that the bloodline always bred true. There were no half-Tieflings, with any intermixing always resulting in a full-blooded spawn. This became commonly known as the Asmodian Curse or the Devilian plague, and was a cunning tactic by archdevils to infest the mortal planes with their influence. If left unchecked, my people would have steadily outbred all other races and unwittingly brought on a horrible fate to the world at the hands of their patrons. For unbeknownst to all, while many had diverged from the stereotype to serve the evil masters, all Tieflings bare the mark of their infernal legacy and are eternally linked to the hellish planes &amp;ndash; a link that often easily manipulated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The apocalypse never came to pass. As the Tiefling population exploded, hostilities grew between us and the other mortal races. Whispers spread and the most pious leaders began preaching to their followers that the Tieflings were a mark of sin and a demonic blight upon the land. This lead to the First Tiefling Crusade and one of the worst genocides recorded. Tiefling society thereafter would only ever be a shadow of its former self, with those of us fortunate enough to survive scattered or forced into hiding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the centuries that passed, our once-proud race was dogged by our enemies, pushed farther away from the fertile lands and the riches of civilization. Those that remained were driven to a nomadic lifestyle, seeking a land free from prejudice and unrelenting judgment. To this day, a number of factions maintain this way of life, not content to settle in one place too long lest risk being wiped out like many of our ancestors in the crusades. Others found that their infernal resistance allowed them endure the harsh climates and settled in lands ill-suited for other races &amp;ndash; arid deserts, volcanic fields, and even the badlands of the Dead Expanse to the east.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In time, the enduring fury and resentment towards Tieflings dimmed, and we were relegated to the status of an exotic, mysterious breed. However, old prejudices persist, prejudices fed by ancient stereotypes. In the current era, allegiances are defined primarily by a Tiefling’s stance on their origin: there are those who pridefully embrace their heritage and continue to honor the old pacts, and those repulsed by it seeking to distance themselves from the old ways by any means. For the latter, some even resort to the filing of their fangs, painting of their horns, covering of scales, body wrapping of their tails, or, in extreme cases, self-mutilation in order to conceal their devilish features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humans were not the first (nor the last) species to be seduced by Asmodeus’ bargain or other bargains alike. It has long been speculated that the &lt;em&gt;Fey’ri&lt;/em&gt; (fey Fiends), &lt;em&gt;Maeluths&lt;/em&gt; (dwarven devils), &lt;em&gt;Tanarukk&lt;/em&gt; (orcish fiends), and &lt;em&gt;Wisplings&lt;/em&gt; (Halfling devils) were all descended from the archdevils through similar pacts. Although these races share a common ancestry, it has been exceedingly rare for them to harbor any kinship. Even amongst our own kind, Tieflings are inherently distrustful, and in many cases will be more leery of other Tieflings than they would be of other races. The one exception to this would be the Aasimar, who are descended from the celestials. While many Tieflings are indoctrinated at a young age to despise the Aasimar, animosity between the two races has been stoked by a deep, primal instinct of fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legend tells of Tieflings that were able to strike a bargain with the dragons. In return, they mingled their blood with that of the Tieflings, starting the draconic Tiefling bloodline. All children spawned from this bloodline were uniquely gifted in the elemental affinity associated with the dragon parent and made great spellcasters. It is also said that with the introduction of draconic blood, particularly those descended from metallic dragons, actually weakened the ties that bound Tieflings to the hellish planes…&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag><tag>carameldropz</tag><tag>player-author</tag></post><post id="172730299336" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/172730299336" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/172730299336/raven-steals-time" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-04-08 18:25:22 GMT" date="Sun, 08 Apr 2018 11:25:22" unix-timestamp="1523211922" format="markdown" reblog-key="e8oicEYk" slug="raven-steals-time" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Raven Steals Time</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Myth of the Su'krash Dragonborn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
When there is no time, Raven lives in the stars&lt;br/&gt;
Raven listens to the Gods&amp;rsquo; stories of Telisar&lt;br/&gt;
Raven loves the stories, and watches the First People&lt;br/&gt;
But Raven is young, and the young are capricious
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Raven comes down from the stars&lt;br/&gt;
What is this? Raven asks&lt;br/&gt;
This is magic, answers Syf, I create it&lt;br/&gt;
What is this? Raven asks&lt;br/&gt;
This is love, answers Freya, I create it&lt;br/&gt;
What is this? Raven asks&lt;br/&gt;
This is justice, answers Woden, I create it&lt;br/&gt;
I wish to make things also! declares Raven&lt;br/&gt;
Foolish bird, says Mimir, what can you make?&lt;br/&gt;
The gods laugh, and Raven flies away
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Raven flies across the Sea Of Chaos, to Greipani&lt;br/&gt;
Greipani sits, perched on her treasure box&lt;br/&gt;
Atop a mountain of gold&lt;br/&gt;
Her devils bringing endless tribute&lt;br/&gt;
Hello, Green Sister! calls Raven&lt;br/&gt;
Hello Anansus, for I know it is you, says Greipani&lt;br/&gt;
You are very clever, answers Raven, but not so clever as me&lt;br/&gt;
Foolish bird, says Greipani, there are none cleverer than me&lt;br/&gt;
A contest, then! says Raven&lt;br/&gt;
Very well, says Greipani, What is the game?&lt;br/&gt;
The first to trick Angrochinach&amp;rsquo;s sapphire from her clutches&lt;br/&gt;
  must surely be the most clever, says Raven
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Angrochinach has a sapphire the size of a Roc&amp;rsquo;s egg
&lt;br/&gt;
She taunts her sisters with it and prizes it above all else
&lt;br/&gt;
Greipani most of all, who has no sapphires, only gold
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Greipani laughs, I know just how to do it! and flies off
&lt;br/&gt;
But Raven does not follow, Raven has tricked Greipani
&lt;br/&gt;
Raven opens Greipani&amp;rsquo;s treasure box and steals Time
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Raven returns to the gods
&lt;br/&gt;
This is Time, cackles Raven, I create it! Hah!
&lt;br/&gt;
Foolish bird, now stories will have an end, says Mimir
&lt;br/&gt;
The First People will to grow old and die, says Thorus
&lt;br/&gt;
For Time contains an ending to all things&lt;br/&gt;
And Raven wept for his foolishness.
&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag></post><post id="172702671216" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/172702671216" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/172702671216/on-the-war-of-the-sisterhood-and-the-creation-of" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-04-07 22:33:36 GMT" date="Sat, 07 Apr 2018 15:33:36" unix-timestamp="1523140416" format="markdown" reblog-key="QD0HdijQ" slug="on-the-war-of-the-sisterhood-and-the-creation-of" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>On the War Of the Sisterhood and the Creation of The Nine Hells</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;On the subject of the Nine Hells, The Dragonborn have this to say: that before her eternal sleep at
the bottom of the Abyss, Tiamat, despairing the loss of her metallic children to Bahamut and wishing
for companionship, willed five daughters to rise from the waves of the Sea of Chaos: Aegiraxus the
Black, Angrochinach the Blue, Greipani the Green, Karixus the Red, and Gjalpithor the White. &amp;ldquo;Do you
see, Betrayer?&amp;rdquo; shrieked Tiamat into endless Night, knowing Bahamut would hear, &amp;ldquo;My children are
greater and more mighty than yours!&amp;rdquo; Being aspects of Tiamat, and thus borne of hate and envy, the
Sisters immediately fell to scheming and warring amongst themselves, playing cruel tricks, forming
alliances only to betray them, and so on, until even Tiamat tired of their bickering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Su'krash Tribe claim to be descendants of Aegiraxus, incidentally, while the neighboring Halisha
of Telsus Island say they are the daughters of Karixus, which I suppose explains why they are
constantly slaughtering each other over the fishing rights to a few miles of rocky shoreline. In
fact the Halisha say the Sisters even turned on Tiamat, and drove her into the Sea of Chaos; a
suitably matricidal tale from a tribe obsessed with such violent rites of succession. Of course they
blame Aegiraxus as the instigator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to return to our theme: in the manner of all sisters, these Sisters were more alike than they
cared to admit, and this likeness only fueled their competition. As the tale is told they created
the races of chromatic dragons in their own images to fight their wars, lesser than themselves but
still awesome in their power; and these chromatic dragons amassed mighty armies of fiends and pit
them against each other for time beyond counting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These &amp;ldquo;Wars Of The Sisterhood&amp;rdquo; raged across every Plane of existence, it is said, and so terrible
were they that the stars themselves wept, and fell from the heavens in despair. And wherever the
stars fell, their sorrow raged as an inferno, and together these fallen stars created the layers of
the Nine Hells: infinite, empty planes of sorrow and pain. This is no doubt more metaphorical
nonsense from a people who seem to think randomly scratching runes in the dirt constitutes high
literature; the cosmology of the Nine Hells is of course well understood &amp;ndash; refer to my own
Cosmology of the Nine Hells for a thorough accounting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dragonborn say that eventually Bahamut&amp;rsquo;s children, Woden, Syf, Mimir, Thorus and Freya, whom we
call The Five, grew tired of the endless horrors of the Sisters&amp;rsquo; bickering, and decided to
intervene. They created the races of metallic dragons in their image to counter the chromatic
dragons; likewise the celestial races &amp;ndash; the Angels, the Archon and the Eladrin &amp;ndash; they set before
the fiends. Now united by a common enemy, the infernal armies joined together under the leadership
of Baal, first son of Karixus, and met the celestials in battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here at last we begin to approach something resembling an accurate accounting, for as to the
details of the celestials&amp;rsquo; war against the fiends this much at least is supported by the scholar
Anaraxus. In his Tome of Revelation, Anaraxus reports the two armies fought to a standstill,
neither side giving or receiving any quarter, and war seemed everlasting, until at last Bahamut
herself, the Platinum Queen, descended from Mount Celestia and led the Armies Of the Five in a final
assault on Baal&amp;rsquo;s stronghold in Nessus, the Ninth Circle Of Hell. The fiends were defeated utterly,
and imprisoned in the Nine Hells for eternity, and the Five set their armies as eternal guardians
against their escape. Anaraxus further tells us Baal himself was slain by his second-in-command,
Asmodeus, who even now rules as Lord Of Hell, plotting revenge. And every fiend and devil in the
Hells remembers this defeat, and is consumed by hate for the Platinum Queen and all her works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How fascinating it is that the Dragonborn clutch so much apocryphal nonsense to their scaly bosom,
&amp;ndash; weeping stars and burning sorrows, indeed! &amp;ndash; eschewing the primary sources in favour of oral
telling and retelling which must always be incomplete and misleading. Their traditions contain
kernels of truth, but it is so distorted that it is only through the diligence of the careful and
dedicated scholar such as your humble author that fact may be separated from fancy. Verily, the
enlightened reader may refer to my &amp;ldquo;Physiognomy and Taxonomy of Dragons&amp;rdquo; in this very tome for a
cogent rebuttal of the more ridiculous aspects of this account; for Dragonborn are no more fallen
celestials than I am a Mountain Dwarf.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div align="right"&gt;
&amp;ndash; &lt;u&gt;Astrumson’s Guide To Everything&lt;/u&gt;,
&lt;br/&gt;Traumus Astrumson (2183 M.E.)
&lt;/div&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag></post><post id="172682057461" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/172682057461" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/172682057461/episode-11-its-only-the-end-of-the-worlds-again" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-04-07 07:12:09 GMT" date="Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:12:09" unix-timestamp="1523085129" format="markdown" reblog-key="OjpQW0iS" slug="episode-11-its-only-the-end-of-the-worlds-again" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode 11: It’s Only The End of The Worlds Again</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Freydag, 10th of the Bear, 3206 ME (continued)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levani found her discorporated spirit standing on the shores of a black sea, on a beach of black sand under a sky of night. There she was nearly consumed by Rashtek, a lich whose blood pact, the Trajzte ur Flasch, is powered by the souls of tieflings forcibly ejected from their bodies at the moment of death and then consumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rashtek was interrupted and dismissed by an entity who described himself as Anansus, whose aspect was variously an elderly tiefling man, a vast, horizon-spanning black dragon and an immense flock of ravens. Anansus informed Levani that Bahamut, the Platinum Queen of All Creation, had been slain, and that Her death caused a massive explosion across all planes of existence &amp;ndash; this was the explosion that rent a great tear in the skies over Telisar, and was indeed also visible in the Feywild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anansus further charged Levani with a quest to &amp;ldquo;Save the Multiverse,&amp;rdquo; which he claimed was in danger of collapsing in on itself as a result of the damage. To do this, Levani and her friends must collect the pieces of Bahamut&amp;rsquo;s body and rejoin them, that She could be reborn and repair the damage. Anansus then sent her spirit hurtling through the Ethereal plane, where it intersected the Prime Material plane;  she discovered the rest of the party fleeing from the bone devil, which having broken the goblin siege and now covered in mangled, impaled corpses, was rampaging through the streets of Whitebridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party, exhausted and spent from multiple battles was attempting to reach the Temple of Syf, seeking aid against the infernal monster. A pitched, running battle ensued with Ara flinging himself directly into the path of the bone devil, and Levani&amp;rsquo;s spirit, still bound to the Ethereal plane but able to interact with the Prime Material, causing the devil to spontaneously combust. Unable to stop their foe the party looked to be overtaken when Anthol the Elder, Masym, Holy Mother of Syf and a third arrived on the scene. Together with the party they halted the devil, stood it down and eventually banished it back to the Nine Hells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party soon learned that Anthol&amp;rsquo;s companion was Adeptus Practicus Banu, formerly of the El Astrum Public Library, and known to Magnus. Banu, seeing the blue marks on Yuna&amp;rsquo;s skin, led the party to the Hanged Man&amp;rsquo;s Wink tavern, where he quickly dissected one of the blue-skinned hobgoblins, and pulled from its heart a sliver of blue crystal, which he called residium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ara, meanwhile, was assisting the Whitebridge militia in putting out the remaining fires that still burned at the north end of town, the result of the goblin horde&amp;rsquo;s repeated volleys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was revealed that the party had been injected with some sort of refined, liquidated residium, and that it was responsible for several strange effects, including the psychic bond developing between the party members, their apparent ability to instinctually locate one another, and even transporting some of them across great distances, back to the source crystal. Further, the goblins have been manufacturing hobgoblins by somehow corrupting humans with residium crystals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hearing this unlocked a piece of Magnus&amp;rsquo;s memory &amp;ndash; he realized that as a young man some 400 years ago he was obsessed with residium, and uncovering its secrets. This obsession is what led him to the Library, and eventually his enslavement there. He also realized that he was not as free as he thought he was at the destruction of the Library, as the slightest request of  Banu&amp;rsquo;s, a former library Adeptus, compelled Magnus to obey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levani&amp;rsquo;s spirit was able to make contact with the party by using broken glass to etch messages into the wooden floorboards of the tavern, and thus it was that the party learned Levani had been killed, and her remains now lay somewhere in the city of Dis, in the Nine Hells. Banu believed he could restore Levani&amp;rsquo;s spirit to her body, but first they would need to collect it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party settled in for a long rest, preparing to somehow find their way to the Nine Hells and rescue Levani.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Player Hauntings: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jilted Liches: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anthol Ratings: Effective&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magnus&amp;rsquo;s True Age: 400+&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Player Ratings: Awesome&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag></post><post id="172195456586" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/172195456586" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/172195456586/episode-10-bone-thug-and-goblinry" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-03-24 07:11:53 GMT" date="Sat, 24 Mar 2018 00:11:53" unix-timestamp="1521875513" format="markdown" reblog-key="ulcO5zIH" slug="episode-10-bone-thug-and-goblinry" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode 10: Bone Thug and Goblinry</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Freydag, 10th of the Bear, 3206 ME (continued)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failing to successfully avoid a confrontation, the party &amp;ndash; with the aging and mostly ineffectual wizard Anthol the Younger, and without the missing Levani &amp;ndash; took the fight to the camp, slaying several hobgoblins and preparing to face down several more, when a monstrous, giant insectoid creature made of polished bone emerged from the darkness, eviscerating the hobgoblins. Magnus and Ara engaged the bone devil but found their mundane weaponry of little use against the creature. Magnus fell before its vicious attacks, but was revived by Yuna, whose spell sickness was causing unpredictable changes in her spell casting &amp;ndash; now causing spells to fail, now bolstering her health, now quickening her actions allowing for multiple spells at once. The creature mocked the party, rejoicing in its freedom and promising to lay waste to the world. Whether this was mere boast or deadly threat was unclear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, a seething mass of goblinoids was still laying siege to the north gate of Whitebridge. The town militia held the palisade and the north gate, but the goblin archers rained arrows covered in burning pitch down on the town, and the shear force of the horde&amp;rsquo;s numbers left little doubt that the town would soon be overrun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unable to even slow the bone devil, the party eventually retreated, with Keen setting the goblin camp&amp;rsquo;s makeshift tents alight in an attempt to distract. The infernal monster seemed uninterested in pursuing, and instead turned its attention to the goblin horde, a more plentiful meal and presumably less frustrating than the wily and confounding elven monk. The bone devil slammed into the goblin host, unstoppable as hundreds of goblins broke off their attack of the town gates to try and put the devil down. Soon the horde was in complete disarray, with as many goblins fleeing as attemping to break through the gates before being destroyed by the rampaging bone devil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus engaged, neither the goblin host nor the bone devil saw the party make its way around the perimeter to the east, looking for an opportunity to sneak into town and get to a temple for assistance. Unfortunately, as soon as they rounded the corner of the town walls they spied a group of hobgoblins already with grappling gear and ropes with purchase, climbing up and over the walls to enter the town unseen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During these events, the party shared two strange experiences &amp;ndash; the first, each of the party members briefly felt the sensation of being stabbed in the chest, accompanied by a burning sensation on their skin where they had been injected with some blue poison weeks before. Stranger still, the party began to hear each other&amp;rsquo;s thoughts in their head. Yuna seemed to quickly master control of this ability, but the others so far seem unable to keep their thoughts private.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devils Released From An Extra Planar Prison: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Party members missing: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Number of Rounds The DM Forgot To Run His Wizard NPC: All Of Them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Party Rating: Awesome&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag></post><post id="171890782356" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/171890782356" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/171890782356/episode-95-levani-and-tak" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-03-15 07:04:25 GMT" date="Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:04:25" unix-timestamp="1521097465" format="markdown" reblog-key="1P9YwZc9" slug="episode-95-levani-and-tak" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode 9.5: Levani and Tak</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Freydag, 10th of the Bear, 3206 ME (continued)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the party engaged with the hobgoblins outside of Whitebridge, Levani was gripped by a strange magical force and ripped from the material plane. She found herself standing in a summoning circle, in the centre of an underground chamber constructed out of huge stones of baked redish/brown clay. In the chamber with her was an olive-skinned, rakish human bard named Tak, who claimed to have been hired by a wizard to help him retrieve a dangerous artifact. The wizard lied dead at his feet, a charred corpse Tak said was the result of setting off a trap. He had used his last precious possession, a scroll of summoning purchased from a Tebaxi merchant in the city of Dis, to attempt to call a bone devil to his aid. Instead, he got Levani. &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re much more beautiful than a bone devil, so it&amp;rsquo;s a shame we&amp;rsquo;re both about to die,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was then that a swarm of iridescent horned beetles began pouring into the room around a set of barred metal doors, so Tak and Levani made their way deeper into the citadel, searching for a way out. Occasionally they were cornered and had to fight their way out as they made their way from room to room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One chamber was little more than a pit of viscous green acid; a tiny platform floated in midair at the centre. Using clever combinations of Mage Hand, her ring of reducing and briefly convincing Tak to wear the Hat of True Frog, Levani was able to get across the chamber, with the swarms of beetles in pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their route led them to a seeming dead end; a desparate last stand against a scarab golem composed of thousands of beetles saw Levani and Tak nearly killed. At the last moment, Tak stepped forward to engage the golem and allow Levani to escape. Faced with a choice of fleeing or attempting to rescue Tak, Levani made a grab for her new ally and dragged him to safety just as the way shut behind them, at least temporarily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final chamber they discovered a huge green gemstone suspended in a beam of light over a raised dias with intricate designs carved into the floor. Levani searched the room for another way out, discovering an illusonary wall at one end, but Tak took this opening and plunged a poison-tipped dagger into her, and dragged her ruined body to the top of the dias, were her blood pooled in the floor carvings thereby releasing the gem from its magical prison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tak disappeared with the gem, leaving Levani unconscious and bleeding out on the floor of the citadel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beetles Roasted: hundreds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gems Recovered: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Piccolo Mandolins Destroyed: Jolina&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Player Character Deaths: ???&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag><tag>levani</tag></post><post id="171719204111" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/171719204111" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/171719204111/episode-9-cheats-and-consequences" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-03-10 08:31:11 GMT" date="Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:31:11" unix-timestamp="1520670671" format="markdown" reblog-key="g9wRfV7u" slug="episode-9-cheats-and-consequences" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode 9: Cheats and Consequences</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Freydag, 10th of the Bear, 3206 ME&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party, with some begrudging help from the aging Dwarven wizard  Anthol Antholson, solved the riddle of the faerie ring and met its constructor, an irridescent indigo fairy dragon named Lord Shimmerscale. Drawn out by Yuna&amp;rsquo;s celestial nature, Shimmerscale revealed himself to the group, and demanded they stay and play more &amp;ldquo;games.&amp;rdquo; Keen made a deal with the fae, and played Shimmerscale for their freedom, cheating him at cards not once but twice. None the wiser and true to his word the fae creature allowed them safe passage out of the Feywild back to the material plane. The party returned to the forest north of Whitebridge, and discovered that despite having spent only a short time in the Feywild weeks had passed in Telisar. And Ara has no memory of what transpired there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party made their way back towards Whitebridge, where they discovered the town aflame, and the south gate under attack by a large horde of goblins. A small war camp had been raised between the edge of the forest and the town;Keen raised the hood on his Cloak of Elven Kind and snuck down to the camp and observed goblin runners  ferrying orders from a tall, blue-skinned hobgoblin in plate armor to the attacking host.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party attempted to sneak past the camp, with Levani disguised as a goblin and attempting to distract them. Despite a cunning disguise involving a Ring of Reduction and Disguise Self, Levani&amp;rsquo;s ruse was revealed when she shouted in Common at the hobgoblin warlord, who dispatched two more hobgoblins to chase after her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile on the other side of the camp the remaining party attempted to use the diversion to sneak past, but Yuna, momentarily losing self control due to her spell-sickness, yelled out in excitement and revealed their location. The group now stands toe-to-toe with a large blue hobgoblin, while the host continues its assault and the town burns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arrogant Wizards Beaten Unconscious: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weeks Spent In The Feywild: 11!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sods Who Roll Natural 20s On Investigation Checks That Revealed the Key To Solving A Fairy&amp;rsquo;s Riddle Rating: Lucky.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag></post><post id="171498181411" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/171498181411" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/171498181411/tiamat-and-the-lords-of-the-abyss" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-03-03 23:15:57 GMT" date="Sat, 03 Mar 2018 15:15:57" unix-timestamp="1520118957" format="markdown" reblog-key="rjoPNsHE" slug="tiamat-and-the-lords-of-the-abyss" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Tiamat And The Lords Of The Abyss</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As recorded in the Tome Of Revelation, set down by Anaraxus The Foul, Hierophant of the Cult Of The Dragon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiamat the Scorned was cast out from her family by Bahamut Falsefire, Mother of Lies, for no crime
besides willing her children to be strong. The Rainbow Queen flew alone across the surface of the
Sea of Chaos, until at last she could bare her broken heart no longer, and despairing, plunged into
the swirling depths whence she was borne, seeking to be unmade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But so great was her anguish that she could not die; and her tears continued to flow even as she
descended deeper and deeper into the darkness. And as Tiamat wept each tear joined its neighbour,
and froze, and the frozen shards too joined together, forming vast planes of crystal. And as they
grew larger, they sank to the very bottom of Chaos, and passed through it, and there in the void
beyond Chaos itself they formed the Infinite Layers Of The Abyss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding no solace even in primordial Chaos, Tiamat laid to rest at the bottom of the empty Abyss,
alone and cold for ages beyond counting, Tiamat slept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiamat dreamed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So powerful were Tiamat&amp;rsquo;s dreams that they sprang forth, giving rage and hate and despair physical
form; thus were borne the Five Demon Lords of the Abyss: Abraxas, The Unfathomable, Lord of Truth;
Orcus, The Undying, Lord of The Undead; Baphomet, The Hunter, Lord of Beasts; Dagon, The Drowned,
Lord of The Depths; and the eldest, mightest of them all: Demogorgon, The Despairing One, Lord Of
The Abyss, Father Of Demons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they were beings of pure anger and sadness, The Lords immediately fell to fighting, warring for
control over the frozen wastes of the Abyss. Soon they summoned to their sides great armies of
Tanar'ri, the demon races that populate the Abyss even now, and before the Tanar'ri the Lords set
mighty generals, the Obyriths, whose cruelty and horror cowed even demons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For time beyond reckoning the War Of The Abyss raged, until at last the armies were at a standstill;
Demogorgon held the lowest depths of the Abyss, his army the strongest, and his power unchallenged,
while his four brothers schemed and plotted and betrayed one another in endless attempts to usurp
his rule from the Layers above. For beneath the Sea Of Chaos, they were all trapped in the Abyss;
there was simply nowhere else for them to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to this day every demon of the Abyss, whether Lord or dretch, remembers the dreams of the Mother
that gave them life: dreams of revenge against Bahamut, her ungrateful children, and us, the peoples
of Telisar; we who are the vile progeny of betrayal and lies. They hate us, and they are right to,
for we are evil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tiamat sleeps. But one day, Tiamat will awaken to unite the armies of the Abyss, and bring them
forth out of Chaos. And on that day, the Rainbow Queen will slay the Mother Of Lies, and this world
will know destruction, and she will have justice.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag></post><post id="171228046871" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/171228046871" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/171228046871/the-fairy-ring-discovered-by-the-party-in-episode" type="photo" date-gmt="2018-02-24 08:24:06 GMT" date="Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:24:06" unix-timestamp="1519460646" format="markdown" reblog-key="08aKgR4Q" slug="the-fairy-ring-discovered-by-the-party-in-episode" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles" width="720" height="960"><photo-caption>&lt;p&gt;The fairy ring discovered by the party in Episode Eight.&lt;/p&gt;</photo-caption><photo-url max-width="1280">https://78.media.tumblr.com/46f39af97ea84fd5dabb6d360abc9ee1/tumblr_p4nbc6CM7x1wllbxoo1_1280.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="500">https://78.media.tumblr.com/46f39af97ea84fd5dabb6d360abc9ee1/tumblr_p4nbc6CM7x1wllbxoo1_500.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="400">https://78.media.tumblr.com/46f39af97ea84fd5dabb6d360abc9ee1/tumblr_p4nbc6CM7x1wllbxoo1_400.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="250">https://78.media.tumblr.com/46f39af97ea84fd5dabb6d360abc9ee1/tumblr_p4nbc6CM7x1wllbxoo1_250.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="100">https://78.media.tumblr.com/46f39af97ea84fd5dabb6d360abc9ee1/tumblr_p4nbc6CM7x1wllbxoo1_100.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="75">https://78.media.tumblr.com/46f39af97ea84fd5dabb6d360abc9ee1/tumblr_p4nbc6CM7x1wllbxoo1_75sq.jpg</photo-url><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag></post><post id="171227859401" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/171227859401" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/171227859401/episode-eight-false-gods-and-fast-frogs" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-02-24 08:14:55 GMT" date="Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:14:55" unix-timestamp="1519460095" format="markdown" reblog-key="WtfcrrOM" slug="episode-eight-false-gods-and-fast-frogs" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode Eight: False Gods and Fast Frogs</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Freydag, 45th Of The Lion, 3206 ME&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ara further explored the cavern he found himself in. He discovered the goblins he had fought had some sort of old surgical wound, as if something had been embedded under the skin. Eventually Ara encountered the Myconid, a fungal race of  with a group consciousness previously met by Magnus. They gave Ara a vision of goblins deep in the bowels of the earth, in a large, partially-collapsed stone building, hacking and stomping on the Myconid&amp;rsquo;s fungal body. Ara learned his mind was resisting joining the group consciousness; their efforts were blocked somehow. And as suddenly as he disappeared from the group, he reappeared in the cellar of the tavern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the party decoded the mysterious pages they had found, and discovered they contained instructions for making a &amp;ldquo;dead drop;&amp;rdquo; a method for selling and trading goods in the open world, without the need for a fence or carting items to a town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deeply unsettled by recent events, upon his return Ara decided to leave the party and made to go, but was convinced to stay by news of the attempted murder of Keen during his absence. It was then that Levani, through novel combination of Thaumaturgy, Message and subtle casting, penetrated Ara&amp;rsquo;s mind, pretending to be the voice of Rillifane. Thus disguised, she convinced Ara he was on a holy quest to protect the party, and that travelling with them would lead to enlightenment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party had a sore but uneventful night. In the morning they kept their appointment with Masym, priestess of Syf, in the hopes of learning something about the rent in the sky, the visions of goblins and myconid, and the blue potion they had been injected with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Masym told the party of Moradin Kinslayer, the first Dwarf, who was said to have founded the twin cities of High and Low Thorimfel  millenia ago, and of the cataclysmic destruction of the cities as punishment for Moradin&amp;rsquo;s hubris, an act on the scale of recent events, but not especially revealing otherwise. She did suggest that the party might find answers if they could discover the ruins of Low Thorimfel, which she thought might be under the Stone Forest, an area of rocky hills north and west of Whitebridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Masym informed Yuna that her condition, which she called being &amp;ldquo;spellsick,&amp;rdquo; would continue unless she could find a guide to help her channel her divine powers, and learn to control them. Yuna said nothing to the party about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before they left, Masym cast a Greater Restoration on Magnus, attempting to help him recover his lost memories. He had a brief flash of working in his study as a young man, but could not recall details. She said that some powerful magical block was preventing him from remembering what he had forgotten. With time, he may recover more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party left Whitebridge and travelled north, back into the forest, on the trail of Anthol the Younger. They discovered a fairy ring in a large, circular meadow deep in the forest, surrround by strange and unfamiliar vegetation. Magus noted there were four moons in the sky, though the tear remained unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fairy ring contained five stone hands with index fingers extended, and a sixth holding a large brass plate, on which were five oversized brass rings with stones of different colors. There was also a frog wearing a frog hat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ara took one of the rings and placed it on one of the stone fingers, which caused a firey explosion from a prismatic wall that enclosed the meadow. The damage killed the frog, which immediately reverted to the form of an eldery Dwarf, now unconscious. Yuna healed the party, including the Dwarf, who turned back into a frog the moment he regained consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gods Impersonated: One&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lengthy NPC Monologues Avoided: Zero&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weather Forecast: Capricious&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Myconid Rating: Joy&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag></post><post id="171226847186" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/171226847186" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/171226847186/the-tale-of-moradin-kinslayer" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-02-24 07:25:50 GMT" date="Fri, 23 Feb 2018 23:25:50" unix-timestamp="1519457150" format="markdown" reblog-key="npCrMJKR" slug="the-tale-of-moradin-kinslayer" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>The Tale Of Moradin Kinslayer</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A story told by Holy Mother Masym, Priestess of Syf&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reckon the days of the Modern Era beginning three millenia ago when the Dwarves of the East first
landed on the shores of Telisar, sailing the tides of woe and war. Most people believe these were
the first Dwarves to walk this land. But most people have forgotten the Tale of Moradin Kinslayer.
This is the tale I will tell you now, even as Woden, Father of Justice told it to his brothers
and sisters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By Woden&amp;rsquo;s divine word was Moradin, the first dwarf, hewn from solid rock and given life.  As Woden
told it, Moradin made his home here, high in the Redfall Mountains of Telisar; so taken was he with
the beauty of the land the Gods had fashioned that he was inspired to add his own creations to it,
and so he cut each dwarf from the mountain stone with his mighty war pick, Grendel.  This is why
Moradin was called Moradin Lifecarver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was very long ago, in the ages before the Modern Era began. Here, high in the mountains and
away from the other races, Moradin taught the dwarves how to mine, and smith, and work metals. For
centuries, Moradin&amp;rsquo;s Kin shaped the mountains into the twin cities of High and Low Thorimfel,
carving and levelling and working the very bedrock, pulling riches from the ground and fashioning
grand works of art and engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Moradin Lifecarver grew bold, and bade his Kin descend the mountains, to take the South Pass to
the plains and subjagate the folk that lived there, for were not the dwarves the mightiest, most
perfect of all the races? Was not their story the greatest? The dwarves obeyed, and Moradin&amp;rsquo;s Kin
came down out of the mountains, their vanguard atop mighty gryphons, with Moradin at their lead,
and there was war in Telisar for the first time. This is why Woden is also called Father Of War.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But seeing this, Woden grew angry, for it is a poor thing to raise oneself up by driving your
neighbour into the mud, and he loved not his new divine aspect. And so as Woden told it a great
meteor rent the skies above mighty Thorimfel. So great was it that the force of its coming split the
meteor in two: one half sundered High Thorimfel utterly; the city, and the mountainside from which
it was carved, shattered and fell away into the sea, leaving only the sheer drop of the Cliffs Of
White. The other half splintered in the air, and rained fire and destruction down on Low Thorimfel.
What portions of the city that were not completely destroyed were buried, lost forever under
avalanches of stone and earth miles across, as the mountains collapsed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so Moradin Lifecarver, in his folly and hubris, became Moradin Kinslayer. He retreated from the
world in despair, into the Endless Night where dwell all the Gods of this realm, and from that day
to this has never again stood on the stones of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without their general, the Dwarven armies were defeated, slain to the last man. And the Iron Gates
that now guard Kinslayer Pass were raised, and closed, as a bulwark against any other Redfall Dwarf
that should seek to march on the free peoples of Telisar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is a legend that some dwarves survived the destruction of Thorimfel, living on in darkness
under the mountains, their city forever buried, and their hearts returned to stone. Whether there is truth to this I know not, but long
is the story of Telisar, and unfinished; perhaps this tale is not yet done.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag></post><post id="171033732106" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/171033732106" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/171033732106/some-mysterious-sheaves-of-paper-discovered-in-a" type="photo" date-gmt="2018-02-19 00:49:16 GMT" date="Sun, 18 Feb 2018 16:49:16" unix-timestamp="1519001356" format="markdown" reblog-key="XKm9PiWI" slug="some-mysterious-sheaves-of-paper-discovered-in-a" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles" width="3456" height="4608"><photo-caption>&lt;p&gt;Some mysterious sheaves of paper discovered in a nook in the cellar of the Hanged Man&amp;rsquo;s Wink.&lt;/p&gt;</photo-caption><photo-url max-width="1280">https://78.media.tumblr.com/71eb87262c6c621654c6f28cc2353cbd/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo1_1280.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="500">https://78.media.tumblr.com/71eb87262c6c621654c6f28cc2353cbd/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo1_500.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="400">https://78.media.tumblr.com/71eb87262c6c621654c6f28cc2353cbd/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo1_400.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="250">https://78.media.tumblr.com/71eb87262c6c621654c6f28cc2353cbd/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo1_250.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="100">https://78.media.tumblr.com/71eb87262c6c621654c6f28cc2353cbd/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo1_100.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="75">https://78.media.tumblr.com/71eb87262c6c621654c6f28cc2353cbd/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo1_75sq.jpg</photo-url><photoset><photo offset="o1" caption="" width="3456" height="4608"><photo-url max-width="1280">https://78.media.tumblr.com/71eb87262c6c621654c6f28cc2353cbd/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo1_1280.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="500">https://78.media.tumblr.com/71eb87262c6c621654c6f28cc2353cbd/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo1_500.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="400">https://78.media.tumblr.com/71eb87262c6c621654c6f28cc2353cbd/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo1_400.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="250">https://78.media.tumblr.com/71eb87262c6c621654c6f28cc2353cbd/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo1_250.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="100">https://78.media.tumblr.com/71eb87262c6c621654c6f28cc2353cbd/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo1_100.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="75">https://78.media.tumblr.com/71eb87262c6c621654c6f28cc2353cbd/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo1_75sq.jpg</photo-url></photo><photo offset="o2" caption="" width="3456" height="4608"><photo-url max-width="1280">https://78.media.tumblr.com/b072de828b0e13838ae144a8ae8ca0cb/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo2_1280.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="500">https://78.media.tumblr.com/b072de828b0e13838ae144a8ae8ca0cb/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo2_500.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="400">https://78.media.tumblr.com/b072de828b0e13838ae144a8ae8ca0cb/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo2_400.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="250">https://78.media.tumblr.com/b072de828b0e13838ae144a8ae8ca0cb/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo2_250.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="100">https://78.media.tumblr.com/b072de828b0e13838ae144a8ae8ca0cb/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo2_100.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="75">https://78.media.tumblr.com/b072de828b0e13838ae144a8ae8ca0cb/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo2_75sq.jpg</photo-url></photo><photo offset="o3" caption="" width="3456" height="4608"><photo-url max-width="1280">https://78.media.tumblr.com/6edc76824d87596dfdc50a63a4c12da7/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo3_1280.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="500">https://78.media.tumblr.com/6edc76824d87596dfdc50a63a4c12da7/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo3_500.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="400">https://78.media.tumblr.com/6edc76824d87596dfdc50a63a4c12da7/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo3_400.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="250">https://78.media.tumblr.com/6edc76824d87596dfdc50a63a4c12da7/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo3_250.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="100">https://78.media.tumblr.com/6edc76824d87596dfdc50a63a4c12da7/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo3_100.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="75">https://78.media.tumblr.com/6edc76824d87596dfdc50a63a4c12da7/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo3_75sq.jpg</photo-url></photo><photo offset="o4" caption="" width="3456" height="4608"><photo-url max-width="1280">https://78.media.tumblr.com/c3a243ce63f085ea4da0aaaa0f71937f/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo4_1280.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="500">https://78.media.tumblr.com/c3a243ce63f085ea4da0aaaa0f71937f/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo4_500.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="400">https://78.media.tumblr.com/c3a243ce63f085ea4da0aaaa0f71937f/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo4_400.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="250">https://78.media.tumblr.com/c3a243ce63f085ea4da0aaaa0f71937f/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo4_250.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="100">https://78.media.tumblr.com/c3a243ce63f085ea4da0aaaa0f71937f/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo4_100.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="75">https://78.media.tumblr.com/c3a243ce63f085ea4da0aaaa0f71937f/tumblr_p4dgy4Rxgi1wllbxoo4_75sq.jpg</photo-url></photo></photoset><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag></post><post id="170712573771" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/170712573771" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/170712573771/episode-seven-do-these-dice-really-go-all-the-way" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-02-10 08:11:09 GMT" date="Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:11:09" unix-timestamp="1518250269" format="markdown" reblog-key="QpmAieB6" slug="episode-seven-do-these-dice-really-go-all-the-way" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode Seven: Do These Dice Really Go All The Way To 20?</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thordag, 44th Of The Lion, 3206 ME (continued)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After making a kind of peace with the Whitebridge Thieves Guild, the party learned that Keen was wanted for the murder of his circus performing partner, Able. Keen asserted his innocence, with mixed reactions from the group. The party then considered what to do about Keen&amp;rsquo;s bounty, since the Thieves Guild had already alerted whoever was seeking him. They decided to move the Guild members and the children they were protecting to the guard barracks, in case trouble showed. As they discussed their various options &amp;ndash; do they stay and set up a trap? Do they try to find the missing arcanist Anthol The Younger? Do they go goblin hunting? &amp;ndash; a sudden pain flared in each of them, at the site of the injection they each received when they were kidnapped. And with a popping noise and a faint smell of brimstone, Ara vanished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ara found himself in an underground tunnel, which led slowly down into the earth before opening on a cavern where he met and handily dispatched two of the three goblin guards, the third disappearing down a passage way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in Whitebridge it then started to snow, odd for a later summer day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party returned to the Hanged Man&amp;rsquo;s Wink tavern, where Keen talked the barkeep into opening the Private Reserves, a collection of liquors he procured from some merchant looking to expand their business. At random, Keen choose a firey apple brandy that immediately got him very drunk, and bestowed a minor curse on him that made him unnaturally attracted to tieflings. This made for an interesting conversation with Levani, the party&amp;rsquo;s tiefling sorcerer, before Keen finally passed out and was dragged to his room. Levani picked up Keen&amp;rsquo;s belongings, including the mysterious Dragonhead coin, which she felt compelled to keep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yuna and Levani made their way to the Temple Of Syf, to speak with the clerics about the strange blue discoloration around their injection sites. The cleric Bali was unable to provide much insight, but seeing that many townsfolk still needed healing, Yuna offered her assistance, and in doing so seemed to succumb to some sort of narcotic effect as a result of using her magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Yuna and Levani were out, and Magnus resting, Keen had a brief but deadly encounter with a blue-skinned tiefling woman who snuck into his room, searched him thoroughly and then slit his throat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yuna and Levani arrived just in time to save his life, though the tiefling woman made good her escape, sight unseen. They party moved to the basement of the inn for a nervous long rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RP Rating: Awesome&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saving Throws Failed: Like, all of them, I think?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Children Probably Saved: 31&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag></post><post id="170180160106" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/170180160106" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/170180160106/episode-6-thats-right-we-kill-children-now" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-01-27 07:59:33 GMT" date="Fri, 26 Jan 2018 23:59:33" unix-timestamp="1517039973" format="markdown" reblog-key="qdS3fCQ8" slug="episode-6-thats-right-we-kill-children-now" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode 6: That’s Right, We Kill Children Now</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thordag, 44th Of The Lion, 3206 ME (continued)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yuna awoke in the Hanged Man&amp;rsquo;s Wink tavern, having been left there a few hours earlier by Magnus. She was rested, but not without troubling dreams. Dreams of spiders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She wandered the town of Whitebridge, looking for her friends, and was met by Levani, who told her Magnus, Ara and Keen had taken off after some children, one of whom had stolen Keen&amp;rsquo;s coinpurse. Together they hurried off to try and catch up with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the remainder of the party had been led into a trap by the children, where a deadly encounter ensued, and the party, divided and caught off guard, were nearly dispatched by a small group of teenagers claiming to be the Whitebridge Thieves Guild. The leader of the group, a sullen 17 year old named Quick William, demanded the surrender of Keen, whom he intended to turn in for a bounty of 500 gold. He produced a wanted poster featuring Keen&amp;rsquo;s likeness, and claimed it was capable of a Sending spell, which they had used to tell &lt;em&gt;someone&lt;/em&gt; they had Keen. Blows, then words, then more blows were exchanged, and soon only Keen and William were left standing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The timely arrival of Yuna and Levani and the former&amp;rsquo;s use of the Calm Emotions spell provided an end to the fighting, and Ara, Magnus, and two of the children were saved from death. Keen agreed to surrender on the condition that the children fetch Jules, to help resolve the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keen was dragged down into the Thieves Guild&amp;rsquo;s hideout, where teenagers had been attempting to care for a large group of Whitebridge&amp;rsquo;s abandoned and orphaned children, while the rest of the party remained in the alley awaiting Jules. While they waited, Levani learned from Keen via a message spell that he was wanted for murder; Keen claimed he had been framed. And Magnus taught the children some old timey swear words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attempted murders by children: 3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attemped murders of children: 6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving paintings made of spiders rating: Creepy AF&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag></post><post id="170066597496" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/170066597496" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/170066597496/the-beginnings-of-fate" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-01-24 06:01:22 GMT" date="Tue, 23 Jan 2018 22:01:22" unix-timestamp="1516773682" format="markdown" reblog-key="lJOylWJn" slug="the-beginnings-of-fate" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>The Beginnings Of Fate</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Go on then, brother, tell us more about Garl Glittergold,&amp;rdquo; said Thorus, his laugh the crashing of
thunder across the Night, &amp;ldquo;I like these gnomes he has fashioned!&amp;rdquo; And Woden laughed also, and the
wide, twinkling grin of the gnome god flickered in the flames of the fire around which Bahamut&amp;rsquo;s
Children sat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I have a story,&amp;rdquo; said Syf, and leaned into the light. &amp;ldquo;The peoples of this little world have their
little lives, they live and they die, they worship the gods we have fashioned for them. But why do
these things? What reason have we given them to exist beyond our amusement?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t our amusement enough, sister?&amp;rdquo; said Mimir, and Thorus laughed again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Syf ignored them. &amp;ldquo;In my story, the mortal folk are each given a purpose. Some great, some
humble, but each possessed of their own. And look, look how they fit together!&amp;rdquo; and in the flames
the first threads of fate began to weave together, patterns of shimmering complexity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freya squealed in delight. &amp;ldquo;Oh, how beautiful! Like crystals!&amp;rdquo; and indeed as the Children stared
into the fire the fates joined together in rigid, immovable lattices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Syf said, &amp;ldquo;But to have destiny without the means to change it makes for a poor story, for the
endings are all written before they begin. That&amp;rsquo;s why they have not just fate, but will. And with
will comes magic, the expresion of will.&amp;rdquo; As she spoke, the crystaline lattices of fate twisted, and
broke, each line now twisting and warping, ever-changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mimir leaned closer, entranced. &amp;ldquo;What are they doing?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Syf smiled and said, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it wonderful?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag></post><post id="169915281751" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/169915281751" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/169915281751/episode-5-respite-in-whitebridge" type="regular" date-gmt="2018-01-20 08:34:08 GMT" date="Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:34:08" unix-timestamp="1516437248" format="markdown" reblog-key="ltFtmhad" slug="episode-5-respite-in-whitebridge" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode 5: Respite In Whitebridge</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thordag, 44th Of The Lion, 3206 ME&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the party lay stunned by the devastation the explosion in the sky wrought all around them, Keen
let out a yelp and pulled off his boot. And from it tumbled an oversized gold coin,
inexplicably glowing white hot, to land in the dirt. Keen told the party he won the Dragonhead in a
card game; &amp;ldquo;I saw it, I wanted it, so I got it.&amp;rdquo; As the coin cooled, Keen reached to pick it up and
discovered that where previously both faces of the coin featured a stylized dragon&amp;rsquo;s head, one side
was now completely smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magnus told the party of a theory he had heard, held by some scholars, that the reason society never
seemed to progress was that as civilization developed, some great calamity would befall the land and
civilization would be crushed. He speculated that something on the scale of what had just occurred
could be such a calamity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was revealed that both Magnus and Keen had worked at a circus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party elected to camp for the night in place. The night passed uneventfully, but they awoke to
discover that the sky looked the same as before they slept, as though time had not passed. Troubled,
they set off over the debris of a ruined forest that had been shattered and collapsed for as far as
they could see. After some hours of slow going the day seemed to &amp;ldquo;catch up,&amp;rdquo; and wheeled quickly
into dawn, though the aftermath of the explosion remained fixed in the sky. They emerged beyond the
edge of the devastation and made their way South to the town of Whitebridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They were met at the gates by Elres, Captain of the guard, and welcomed in &amp;ndash; word of their
adventure at Greencrack Copper Mine preceded them with Jules, who had apparently returned safely
with the survivors the previous night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yuna, who had woken feeling weakened, exhausted and feverish made her way to The Hanged Man&amp;rsquo;s Wink,
a tavern and inn just inside the gates, to rest, while the remainder of the party was briefly
reunited with Jules, the bearded dwarven rogue who turned out to be Julia, daughter to Ultar
Greencrack. Ultar asked the party to return to the family&amp;rsquo;s mine to liberate it from the Kobold
Mother and the remains of the tribe, though Jules confided that she felt the mine was lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeking to learn all they could about recent events, the party encountered a crowd of terrified,
panicked townsfolk at the foot of the Temple Of Syf. The crowd was calmed by words from Masym, The
Holy Mother, and as it dispersed Magnus met Ambriel, a young acolyte, who invited them to return in
the morning to speak with Masym about the history of the town, and the Thorimfel Plateau.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levani, following advice from Ultar Greencrack, led the party to Anthol&amp;rsquo;s Emporium Of Arcana and met
the proprietor. The ancient dwarf did not have much knowledge to offer and seemed unaware that
anything untoward had even occurred outside,  but the party did learn that the ruins of the city of
Thorimfel were not in fact under Whitebridge but a few days&amp;rsquo; travel away. Anthol also said his son
(Anthol) had left some days ago to investigate rumours of a fairy ring that appeared in
the woods. Purchasing a map of the Thorimfel Plateau, they left the shop and considered what to do
next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anthols Met: 1/??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maps Acquired: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dwarves Misgendered: 1/??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RP Rating: Awesome&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag></post><post id="169914218111" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/169914218111" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/169914218111" type="photo" date-gmt="2018-01-20 07:41:04 GMT" date="Fri, 19 Jan 2018 23:41:04" unix-timestamp="1516434064" format="markdown" reblog-key="h1S5UdN1" slug="" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles" width="3456" height="4608"><photo-url max-width="1280">https://78.media.tumblr.com/2be0b204692f70c100b3f998e2d7091a/tumblr_p2ug0gzpQq1wllbxoo1_1280.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="500">https://78.media.tumblr.com/2be0b204692f70c100b3f998e2d7091a/tumblr_p2ug0gzpQq1wllbxoo1_500.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="400">https://78.media.tumblr.com/2be0b204692f70c100b3f998e2d7091a/tumblr_p2ug0gzpQq1wllbxoo1_400.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="250">https://78.media.tumblr.com/2be0b204692f70c100b3f998e2d7091a/tumblr_p2ug0gzpQq1wllbxoo1_250.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="100">https://78.media.tumblr.com/2be0b204692f70c100b3f998e2d7091a/tumblr_p2ug0gzpQq1wllbxoo1_100.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="75">https://78.media.tumblr.com/2be0b204692f70c100b3f998e2d7091a/tumblr_p2ug0gzpQq1wllbxoo1_75sq.jpg</photo-url><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag></post><post id="168804363241" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804363241" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804363241/the-myth-of-creation" type="regular" date-gmt="2017-12-22 01:33:16 GMT" date="Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:33:16" unix-timestamp="1513906396" format="markdown" reblog-key="WwQRFK0t" slug="the-myth-of-creation" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>The Myth of Creation</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is the story of creation, as told by denizens of Telisar.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many worlds beside this one. Between the planes of existence flows the Sea Of Chaos, a boundless, formless ocean of potential. The first thing that happened was this: Bahamut emerged from the waves in the form of an infinite platinum-scaled dragon, Her great glistening metallic wings radiating light across the surface of the Sea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bahamut flew over the Sea, but no matter how far She ranged She found Herself alone. Despairing for companionship, the Platinum Queen willed Tiamat rise from waves, and so the second thing that happened was this: the Rainbow Queen was borne of Chaos. Tiamat emerged as a five-headed dragon of many colors, Her heads snapping and fighting, and Bahamut was glad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together Bahamut and Tiamat danced through the Endless Night above the Sea Of Chaos, their love igniting the stars. Tiamat used the stars to fashion the constellations, and Bahamut, delighted, named each one: The Fox, The Eagle, The Raven, and the rest. This was the third thing that happened: The Queens Of Night made the stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this was the fourth thing that happened: With Tiamat, Bahamut begat five children. From Bahamut was borne Woden, Father Of Brass Dragons; Syf, Mother of Copper Dragons; Mimir, Mother of Gold Dragons; Freya, Mother of Silver Dragons; and Thorus, Father of Bronze Dragons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The children fought, in the manner of all siblings, and while Tiamat delighted in their contests, their conflicts and petty betrayals, Bahamut was saddened. To bring peace amongst them, Bahamut told the children the story of Telisar, and together each child was given a turn to tell a part of the story. This is why to the children are given the names of the days. This was the fifth thing that happened: Telisar was borne of the dreams of dragons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Tiamat grew jealous of their attention, now fixed on Bahamut, and demanded they return to their contests of strength and power, their games of trickery and cunning. But they refused, for the story of Telisar was not yet done, and the Rainbow Queen flew into a rage. Gathering her children around Her, Bahamut cast Tiamat into Night, forbidding her to return. Tiamat flew away across the Sea of Chaos, in her spite vowing to slay Bahamut and win back her children. This was the sixth thing that happened: The Queens Of Night were parted.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag></post><post id="168804340041" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804340041" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804340041/the-telisaran-calendar-syfdag-kindle-fates" type="photo" date-gmt="2017-12-22 01:32:18 GMT" date="Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:32:18" unix-timestamp="1513906338" format="markdown" reblog-key="RvTE0RvS" slug="the-telisaran-calendar-syfdag-kindle-fates" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles" width="540" height="570"><photo-caption>&lt;h2&gt;The Telisaran Calendar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;
Syfdag kindle fate’s first light&lt;br/&gt;
Mimdag have a secret might&lt;br/&gt;
Wodag have the strength to fight&lt;br/&gt;
Thordag curse the wrong, avenge the right&lt;br/&gt;
Freydag love fair beauty’s sight&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
    – Dwarven nursery rhyme
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Telisaran calendar derives from a mixture of the traditions of the Dwarven settlers who reached the Eastern shores of Telisar at the start of the Modern Era, and those of the Dragonborn peoples already there. It reckons the year as eight Seasons of 45 days each. At the end of the year, between 45th of the Bear and 1st of the Fox is the Festival Of The Hunt, a five-day celebration of life, family, and renewal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each season is divided in to 9 weeks of 5 days each; the days are named for the Dwarven pantheon of creator gods:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Syfdag, named for Syf, goddess of destiny, fate and magic&lt;br/&gt;
Mimdag, named for Mimir, goddess of knowledge and wisdom&lt;br/&gt;
Wodag, named for Woden, god of war and death&lt;br/&gt;
Thordag, name for Thorus, god of justice and law&lt;br/&gt;
Freydag, named for Freya, goddess of love, beauty, and life&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Our adventure begins in late autumn, on Syfdag, 41st Of The Lion, 3206 ME.&lt;/p&gt;</photo-caption><photo-url max-width="1280">https://78.media.tumblr.com/abcbcd7cfe10dc4ec7ed1c795d901da3/tumblr_p1c9luKUWL1wllbxoo1_540.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="500">https://78.media.tumblr.com/abcbcd7cfe10dc4ec7ed1c795d901da3/tumblr_p1c9luKUWL1wllbxoo1_500.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="400">https://78.media.tumblr.com/abcbcd7cfe10dc4ec7ed1c795d901da3/tumblr_p1c9luKUWL1wllbxoo1_400.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="250">https://78.media.tumblr.com/abcbcd7cfe10dc4ec7ed1c795d901da3/tumblr_p1c9luKUWL1wllbxoo1_250.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="100">https://78.media.tumblr.com/abcbcd7cfe10dc4ec7ed1c795d901da3/tumblr_p1c9luKUWL1wllbxoo1_100.jpg</photo-url><photo-url max-width="75">https://78.media.tumblr.com/abcbcd7cfe10dc4ec7ed1c795d901da3/tumblr_p1c9luKUWL1wllbxoo1_75sq.jpg</photo-url><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag></post><post id="168804203706" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804203706" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804203706/episode-4-daylight-and-and-distrust" type="regular" date-gmt="2017-12-22 01:27:06 GMT" date="Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:27:06" unix-timestamp="1513906026" format="markdown" reblog-key="Ch6xqCz3" slug="episode-4-daylight-and-and-distrust" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode 4: Daylight and And Distrust</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Wodag, 43th Of The Lion, 3206 ME&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a long, plodding trek out of Greencrack Copper Mine’s excavation pit with a group of freed captives and one surly red-haired dwarven rogue, the party was forced to contend with a flesh golem, constructed out of the rotting carcasses of dead kobolds and summoned forth by an alarm, presumably raised by the kobold that escaped them in the previous battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through judicious use of oil and flame, the golem, having gone berserk and uncontrollable, was brought to the brink of death, when in its madness it clobbered its winged kobold minder. With its dying breaths the kobold triggered some manner of magical explosion, which caught Magnus, Yuna and Ara all in its blast. It also caught the golem, which flew apart into chunks of quivering, still animate meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though perilously close to death, the remaining party members, aided by Jules the rogue, were able to stablize the fallen. Before leaving, Ara pocketed a book that he found next to the kobold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party finally exited the mine into early afternoon on a crisp late summer day, and found themselves on the Thorimfel Plateau, a region far to the north of Telisar, nestled deep in the mountains beyond the city of Uman. Jules bade them farewell, with thanks, and led the freed prisoners toward the town of Whitebridge, most of a day’s travel south. The party moved a short ways into the forest to rest, and recouperate, many of them barely conscious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While resting, unseen by everyone save Yuna, a swarm of tiny black spiders, moving as one in the shape of an eye, appeared to be observing them. When Yuna noticed this, the “eye” winked, and dispersed into the trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party decided to make their way to Whitebridge, now a couple of hours behind the survivors, hoping to make it before morning. On the way they reflected on their experiences thus far, looking for reasons why they might have been targeted, and what unites them beyond circumstance. Questions were raised about the identity of the Seeker, the Flame, the Dragon and the Main Who Did Not Die, though no revelations seemed forthcoming, and nobody seemed ready to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As night fell and the party continued their journey to Whitebridge, a great, blinding, utterly silent explosion filled the sky; streaks of light crossed the darkness emanating outward, and the very Moon itself seemed to suffer some catastrophy, as deep black gashes appeared on its surface. A minute later the party, and indeed the countryside all around them was flattened by an emmense wave of explosive force descending from the heavens. The woods for miles around was shattered, and the party was thrown to the ground, Magnus’s bones all shattering in the process. The explosion now hangs in the sky, bathing the world in an eerie white light and long shadows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Boss Battles Completed: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Death Saving Throws Failed: 4/6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ancient Spell Tomes Discovered: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spider Eyeball Rating: Huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moons Cracked: 1&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag></post><post id="168804190171" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804190171" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804190171/welcome-to-telisar" type="regular" date-gmt="2017-12-22 01:26:36 GMT" date="Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:26:36" unix-timestamp="1513905996" format="markdown" reblog-key="imXK1eio" slug="welcome-to-telisar" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Welcome To Telisar</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The introductory text I sent the party before the campaign’s first session…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Arcani Extus, those bookish scholars pursuing lost lore and deep truths of the universe, believe that Telisar is but one of an infinite number of worlds that make up the Material Plane, that portion of existence where wild, raw philosophical and physical forces coalesce. A thousand years ago the Elven scholar Arcanus Traumus Astrumson published a treatise entitled Astrumson’s Guide To Everything, a polarizing work of which the central thesis was that Telisar was but a material echo of tales told by Gods, and had no legitimate existence beyond “…the campfire musings of an idle, omnipotent consciousness.” “Life,” said the sunny scholar, “[is] therefore arbitrary, pointless and devoid of all meaning.” A follower of Traumus, the Arcanus Snorri Skjardinfel, in her Commentaries On Everything noted that “while this may be true, and Traumus correct, it’s no excuse to let the crops die.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snorri’s hard practicalism is the prevailing attitude amongst the common folk of Telisar, who generally don’t trouble themselves with such rarified thoughts as the origins of existence, leading difficult lives attempting to tame a wilderness that seems largely disinclined to civilization. Outside the few towns and villages able to sustain themselves, Telisar is a dangerous place. Dangerous animals, both mundane and monstrous, roam the wild lands. People, too, eke out violent, brutal lives outside society – brigands and bandits, warlords, tribal chiefs, mad sorcerers and petty hedge wizards are found everywhere, and make travel and trade difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are only two major cities in Telisar, the largest being El Astrum, a grand city-state and home to the El Astrum Public Library, the center of learning and magical study. El Astrum straddles the banks of the great Throm River, on the eastern side of Telisar. The Throm flows north-south, dividing the land; little is known of the great western expanse beyond the banks. Following the Throm north-northwest out of El Astrum, along the eastern bank, is the Great Northern Road. A hardy traveller could follow the Road for weeks, over the Misty Moors and through the Forest of Stars, eventually reaching the base of the Redfall Mountains. There, at the mouth of the Throm and beneath a massive waterfall lies the city of Uman. Known as the Jewel Of Redfall, Uman is a city of wealth, its great houses made rich by centuries of mining of precious metals. A thriving merchant class handles trade with El Astrum, moving precious metals, gems, timber, coal, and other raw materials out of the mountains, down the Throm or along the Great Northern Road in huge caravans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The civilized peoples of Telisar are a cross-section of many races, including Humans, Elves, Halflings and Gnomes, even Tieflings, though these latter are considered exotic by most commoners. And then there are the Dragonborn, though they are rarely seen in the modern era. Dragonborn are highly xenophobic, and call Telisar “The First Land,” claiming the land was stolen from them by Dwarven war-priests and their armies thousands of years ago. It is said that what remains of the Dragonborn society retreated far into the west, away from the settlements of the other races; whether this is true is open to debate. Many scholars believe the Dragonborn were for all practical purposes wiped out, and those few that remain are the last vestiges of a dying race.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what would be accounted as common knowledge in Telisar; what mysteries, what secrets and truths might be waiting to be uncovered? Let’s find out.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag></post><post id="168804166981" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804166981" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804166981/magnuss-dream" type="regular" date-gmt="2017-12-22 01:25:43 GMT" date="Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:25:43" unix-timestamp="1513905943" format="markdown" reblog-key="4cJtMbjj" slug="magnuss-dream" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Magnus’s Dream</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;You leave this place, this vault. You fly overground, across hills and stone and rock, and plummet down into the Earth, seeking joy. You feel your body extend, for miles, all through the earth. The warmth and the colours take hold, and you hear your own voice, raised in a chorus of echoes a thousand thousand times: “We are joy,” it says, “Your joy was lost for a time, but we are returned.” And you feel; you know, know the joy as the truth at the core of yourselves, and you are at peace for a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is a sorrow: a sharpness, a loss of yourself, far away. Faintly it ripples through your body, and you shudder. And you push out with your mind, through space, through earth, through luminescent caverns, through light and racing water and through an arch of stone and a walkway and up over the side of a great stone building. Further, through the collapsed roof where you see many of the Lost stumble, disconnected, singular, apart. They must know such pain, to have no joy, and you grieve for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the Lost is among your body, crushing blindly, each step upon you bringing a fresh ripple of sharp sorrow. And so you breathe, you make a gift of your breath, and with it you give joy to the Lost. And its joy is now yours, you are together, finally, and you remember the existence before joy, here in this empty stone building beneath the ground, with the others who were your pack – the Lost. You remember the monolith of great blue crystal, smoky and dark, bursting through the stone floor. You remember the black voice, the terror and the fear, and the instructions it gave your pack. You remember harvesting the crystals, and crushing them, and distilling a deep blue liquid with which to coat tiny darts. You remember sewing shards of the monolith into your flesh, constructing a joy, of sorts, for your pack – a joy you now know to be utterly false – and taking this joy into the empty above, to bring your joy to the others: the dragon, the flame, the seeker, and the man who did not die. But not you, not anymore. Now, here in this place, you are joy.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag><tag>magnus</tag></post><post id="168804155756" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804155756" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804155756/keens-dream" type="regular" date-gmt="2017-12-22 01:25:17 GMT" date="Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:25:17" unix-timestamp="1513905917" format="markdown" reblog-key="O4fj75Ms" slug="keens-dream" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Keen’s Dream</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;You dream of dragons: Dragons filling the sky, moving in great swarms of color; hundreds of them, thousands of them, so many they blot out the sun. Looking up you long to soar, and with a “Woop!” you launch yourself into the air, your great wings spreading out, muscles working like pistons to move the air beneath you. And you climb up, up to the swarm, moving faster and faster as you soar, the wind whipping your face and stinging your eyes, until with a final  push of your mighty wings your burst through the top of the swarm, past dragons of all color and hue, and still you climb, corkscrewing even higher, high and away, your kin falling away behind you, and you exult in your complete and utter freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now your perspective shifts, and instead of pushing straight up into the atmosphere with a lurch in your stomach you realize you are diving, plummeting to the earth; you try to pull up but your wings are no longer your own, pinned to your side. The air screams in your ears as you pick up speed, and you taste panic rising in your gorge as you streak towards the ground. Just as you are about to impact, the earth opens in a horrible tear, a gaping maw of blackness, of chaotic, swirling energy, and with a whoosh you fall straight through.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag><tag>keen</tag></post><post id="168804144381" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804144381" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804144381/levanis-dream" type="regular" date-gmt="2017-12-22 01:24:52 GMT" date="Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:24:52" unix-timestamp="1513905892" format="markdown" reblog-key="fCdBMbmw" slug="levanis-dream" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Levani’s Dream</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;The world around you goes black, and you feel the inky darkness spread across your skin, and crawl up your neck, cover your face, and begin to push into your eyes, your mouth, your nostrils. You instinctively gulp for air and pull more of the darkness inside you. You begin to panic as you feel your lungs filling, your chest burning inside, and the darkness binding your limbs. As you struggle, you see purplish black smoke emanate from the blackness; it is vaguely illuminated, and there is real terror in you now as you watch the smoke and the blackness wind around each other and take on the shape of a familiar face – your face – your golden eyes piercing the darkness. The face speaks, and you hear your own voice in your ears, saying “Trazjte ur Levani, trazjte ur flasch! Rashtek mar tu Levani! You burn, and I see your flame, and it will be MINE.” Your skin ignites, and your body is engulfed in searing flames, and the pain becomes absolute, all consuming.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag><tag>levani</tag></post><post id="168804133866" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804133866" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804133866/aras-dream" type="regular" date-gmt="2017-12-22 01:24:28 GMT" date="Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:24:28" unix-timestamp="1513905868" format="markdown" reblog-key="Tb84Xx08" slug="aras-dream" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Ara’s Dream</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;You are wandering the forest of your youth, the woods nestled deep within which can be found, by those who know to look, the Temple of Rillifane. Every tree, every blade of grass, every flower and plant is familiar. You follow a path from the Temple towards the river, a path you’ve travelled countless times as a boy. Winding down through a copse of ash trees, past the Glen Of Good Morrow, where your master first taught you to meditate; down a sharp cliffside switchback to the water’s edge. You look down into the water, the sunlight glinting off the surface, but instead of your reflection there is only darkness, a silhouette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You look up, and it is night, and in the logic of dreams the river is a road, paved with silvery stones. You begin to follow the road up, up, up, cresting the top of a hill. And before you stands a monstrous, towering oak tree. It is massive, filling the sky, the stars twinkling from within the leaves. The starlight dapples the shimmering river stones with long shadows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite its massive size, the tree is oddly distant. It does not, it cannot see you. It cannot even conceive of something so infinitesimally small as you. You feel a coldness seep into your bones, and you look around, and realize you are completely, utterly alone.&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>lore</tag><tag>ara</tag></post><post id="168804109931" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804109931" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804109931/episode-three-daggers-and-dreams" type="regular" date-gmt="2017-12-22 01:23:34 GMT" date="Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:23:34" unix-timestamp="1513905814" format="markdown" reblog-key="U5tHrc9v" slug="episode-three-daggers-and-dreams" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode Three: Daggers And Dreams</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Wodag, 43th Of The Lion, 3206 ME&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holed up in an empty treasure vault, the party risks a rest to recover their strength and heal. Not long into their rest Magnus discovers them, though bloodied and near death himself. Magnus begins inspecting his wounds, and scraping some spores off. He stuffs something slightly glowing (moss? lichen?) into the larger wounds and binds that into place. It doesn’t look particularly well done. They party has a brief discussion about what might have led to their goblin captors to choose them in particular, but no answers are yet forthcoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During their rest Levani, Keen and Ara each have disturbing, unsettling dreams, though none of them choose to share the particulars with their companions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party wakes to sounds of a search being conducted; their escape having been discovered, and the kobold jailer Dreck having gone missing. Still searching for their weapons, the party makes their way deeper into the tunnels and discover a vast mining pit, where they do battle with a horde of kobolds, who have taken the party’s weapons for their own. The kobolds are defeated with the help of a brusque, short-tempered dwarf, striking out from the shadows and thinning the enemy ranks. The dwarf, Jules, and Keen nearly come to blows during the fray, and as a result a single kobold makes its escape deeper into the mine. The party frees several prisoners, whom the kobolds have pressed into service as miners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jules tells the party that the mine belongs to their family, and they aim to reclaim it from the Kobold tribe and its matriarch, the Mother, but not before leading the freed prisoners to safety. Together with Jules and the prisoners, the party begins a long trek up into the darkness, back to the surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weapons Recovered: most?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kobolds slain: 12&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Innocents killed: 2 (1 human, 1 barrel of drinking water)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dwarven accents murdered: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dreams: weird&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag></post><post id="168804096716" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804096716" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804096716/episode-two-sick-lizards-and-bug-baskets" type="regular" date-gmt="2017-12-22 01:23:06 GMT" date="Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:23:06" unix-timestamp="1513905786" format="markdown" reblog-key="PSEnN0Nw" slug="episode-two-sick-lizards-and-bug-baskets" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode Two: Sick Lizards And Bug Baskets</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mimdag, 42nd Of The Lion, 3206 ME&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party, shaken from their unexpected encounter, take a moment to compose themselves. Keen takes the fallen Kobolds’ daggers, and Yuna, feeling strangely euphoric, pockets a handful of ashes from the Kobold she incinerated. Keen and Magnus discuss how it seemed almost too easy to dispatch these foes, when suddenly Magnus tenses, clutches his neck and disappears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Levani, still disguised as a Kobold, leads the party through the hallway, where they briefly investigate the kitchens before descending a long, dark stairwell deep into the bedrock below ground. At the base of the staircase the party is discovered by a pair of Kobold guards, who find Levani’s arcane disguise unconvincing and are quickly defeated. Ara sees that these Kobolds are sick: pale, jaundiced and weak. Yuna reduces the remaining bodies to ashes for reasons?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party discover a huge treasure vault of Dwarven manufacture, emptied. In the back wall Keen discovers a secret door designed as an escape hatch, leading up, and is prepared to leave, but the party convinces him to stay while they continue to search for their belongings, which they find in the “Armory,” which is little more than a storage room full of mining equipment and random dwarven housewares. Their money and their weapons, however, are still missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party descends deeper underground, following a tunnel broken through the stone walls and into the earth. A basket of giant centipedes drops on them from a hidden recess in the ceiling, and after a brief but deadly encounter, the party decides to reverse course back to the vault and secure themselves there to rest, and ponder the fate of Magnus Stairwell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traps Disarmed: 0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daggers Returned: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passwords Discovered: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paranoia Rating: Awesome&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag></post><post id="168804076351" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804076351" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168804076351/episode-one-grabbed" type="regular" date-gmt="2017-12-22 01:22:21 GMT" date="Thu, 21 Dec 2017 17:22:21" unix-timestamp="1513905741" format="markdown" reblog-key="MBxulW0P" slug="episode-one-grabbed" state="published" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>Episode One: Grabbed!</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Syfdag, 41st Of The Lion, 3206 ME&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magnus, Yuna and Levani are each assaulted by a pack of goblins that appear out of thin air. They are injected with some sort of paralytic, and black out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They awake on a cart, being delivered up a dirt path towards a cavern cut into the side of a miles-long rock wall made of dirty white stone. Inside the cavern they are transferred to the custody of Kobolds, who bring them through a pair of huge metal doors into a large facility and thrown into prison cells, where they encounter Ara and Keen, already imprisoned. They are stripped of their possessions save for a single dagger Levani deftly tosses through the prison bars to Keen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through a combination of trickery, cajoling and threats, the party convinces the kobold minding the prison cells, one Dreck, to release them. Dreck leads them down a long hallway towards “the armory,” where their possessions have been taken. Along the way they pass a closed pair of metal doors, from which emanates a strong stench of rot and decay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magnus releases the terrified Dreck, who disappears, and the party make their way down a long, pitch-black corridor of what seem to be living quarters. Ara stumbles into one room, awakening three sleeping kobolds. The party quickly dispatches the three without waking anyone else, with a combination of luck and quick thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During their escape from the prison cells, the party was getting advice from a voice in one of the other cells. As they progress further into the interior of the facility Yuna realizes that whoever they were talking to is not with them, and in fact nobody saw the speaker at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party now stand over the bodies of the three slain kobolds at the end of the dark corridor, at the end stands an arch. Beyond, there is a low flicker of light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enemies slain: 3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parkour Maneuvers: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stealth Rating: Lucky&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Failed Cart Escapes: 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Light Sources Discovered: 0&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body><tag>dnd</tag><tag>session</tag></post><post id="168803292086" url="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168803292086" url-with-slug="https://the-noobhammer-chronicles.tumblr.com/post/168803292086/the-public-library-of-el-astrum-draft" type="regular" date-gmt="2017-12-22 00:53:57 GMT" date="Thu, 21 Dec 2017 16:53:57" unix-timestamp="1513904037" format="html" reblog-key="fjLZNEXw" slug="the-public-library-of-el-astrum-draft" state="draft" is_reblog="false" tumblelog="the-noobhammer-chronicles"><regular-title>The Public Library of El Astrum -- DRAFT</regular-title><regular-body>&lt;p&gt;Motto: Invenio, Refectio, Concustodio (Invent, Restore, Preserve)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Created as a knowledge store for the free peoples of El Astrum, the library also functioned as a laboratory, warehouse, public forum, zoo, and was open to all, without restriction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Books, preserved entitites, recorded presentations, echos of personalities, free living people, &lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</regular-body></post></posts></tumblr>